片名：家庭阴谋
有人在这里
[Speaking In A Girlish, Dreamy Voice] Someone is here.
不太靠近
Not closely.
不太情愿
Not willingly.
我感到了阻碍
I feel a holding back.
有什么麻烦,亨利?
What's the trouble, Henry?
太多回忆,太多痛苦
[In Deep Male Voice] Too many memories, too much pain.
太多悲伤
Too... much... sorrow.
无论和你在一起的是谁
[In High Voice] Whoever is there with you,
让他们说话,亨利
tell them to speak up, Henry.
让他们靠近一点
Tell them to come closer.
我想我知道那是谁,布兰琪夫人
[Woman #2] I think I know who it is, Madame Blanche.
我想我知道是什么困扰着她
I think I know what's bothering her.
"她",是吗? 别担心,兰伯特女士
[In High Voice] Her, is it? Never you mind, Miss Rainbird.
没有你的指示 亨利不会做任何事的
I won't have you doing Henry's work for him.
现在,让我们一起来吧,亲爱的 这就是为什么今晚我们在这里
Now, let's have it, my love. That's why we're here tonight.
为了帮助我的朋友 摆脱她的痛苦
To help my friend be rid of her torment.
她有休息的权力,让她疲惫的头脑 能在枕头上歇息,于每个晚上…
She has a right to rest her weary head on a pillow each night...
平静地安睡,有如天使
and sleep the peaceful sleep of the angels.
你怎么知道我有睡眠的困扰?
How did you know about my troubled sleep?
- 谁告诉你的? - 她夜晚无法长睡
- Who told you? - Her nights cannot go on like this much longer.
我从来没有告诉别人我的噩梦
I never told a soul about my nightmares.
- 你怎么会… - 是谁来到这里…
- How could you... - Who is this person who arrives...
今晚我们的存在 所以才不敢靠近吗?
in our presence tonight, but does not dare to come close to us?
是她,是我的妹妹哈丽叶
It's her. It's my sister Harriet.
- 绝对是 - 她保持距离
- It must be. - [In Henry's Voice] She stays her distance,
朱莉亚・兰伯特 因为她没有感受到…
Julia Rainbird, for she does not feel...
你的爱或是你的善意
your love or your kindness yet.
你太自私了
There is selfishness where you are.
我已经什么都为她做了
I've had all I can take from her.
她每晚都来到我的梦中
Night after night, coming into my dreams.
发牢骚,抱怨,努力使我感到内疚
Whining, complaining, trying to make me feel guilty,
就好像我需要她来告诉我是非
as though I need her to tell me right from wrong.
告诉她,我知道该怎么做
Tell her I know what has to be done.
我一直想这么做已经一年了
I've been wanting to do it for a year.
但是我,朱莉亚・兰伯特 已经做出决定了
But it is I, Julia Rainbird, who has made the decision.
我不需要她来鞭策我
[Sighing] I don't need her to goad me on!
他们在我梦中丑陋的话语 使我生病
They're making me ill with their ugly words in my ugly dreams.
告诉她该停止了 回去,不要管我
Tell her to stop it, to go away and leave me alone.
喔,不,不,别让她走!
[Stammering] Oh, no. No, no. Don't let her go!
- 别让她离开 - 哈丽叶?
- Don't let her go away. - Harriet?
哈丽叶,留下来,哈丽叶
Harriet, stay with us, Harriet.
你姐姐要和你说话 从她的心灵深处
Your sister wants to speak to you now, from the depths of her soul.
怎么了? 怎么回事?
- What's wrong? What is it? - [Wailing Continues]
她说"我已经等了好久…"
She says, "I've waited so long...
"想听到你说话,朱莉亚"
"to hear from you, Julia.
"没有你在,我很不快乐"
I've been so unhappy without you."
是你,哈丽叶
It is you, Harriet.
喔,我很抱歉
Oh, I'm so sorry!
我不该让你那么做的
I-I should never have made you do it.
喔,都已经过去了
Oh, it's all past now.
但是我会尽我所能地去弥补
But I'll do what I can to make up for it.
如果他还活着 我会找到你的儿子
If he's still alive, I'll find your son.
我会带他到我身边并且爱他
And I'll take him in my arms and love him...
有如我就是你 我可怜的哈利叶
as if I were you, my poor Harriet.
我会…我会待他如己出
And I'll... I'll make him one of us.
给予他一切,一切!
And give him everything. Everything!
离太远了
[Whispering] Far away.
离太远,太远了
So far, far away.
但…但我需要她的协助
Bu-But I need her. I need her help.
我一个人做不到
I can't do it alone.
你看,我需要她的记忆
You see, I need her memory.
那都已经40年了 我不知道孩子被带到哪里…
It's over 40 years ago, and I don't know where the child was taken...
或是送给了谁
or who it was given to.
我不知道他现在在哪里 或他现在是谁
I don't know where he is now or who he is.
对于衡量朱莉亚・兰伯特 真实的爱…
[In Henry's Voice] The true measure of Julia Rainbird's love...
在于她现在要如何去做
lies in what she does now,
藉由你的帮助,当然,还有我的
with your help, of course, and mine,
亲爱的,离开吧…
and that of the dear, departed one...
是谁漂流远离了我们
who has drifted so far from us.
我们了解了,兰伯特女士,对吧?
[In Normal Voice] We understand him. Don't we, Miss Rainbird?
噢,是的,我是 我愿意去做任何事,任何的事
Oh, yes. Yes, I do. I'm willing to do anything. Anything at all.
最后,幸福将会到来
[In Henry's Voice] In the end, there will be happiness.
从逝去的眼泪当中 沙漠般的心灵会开出花朵
From the tears of the past, the desert of the heart will bloom.
再见,朱莉亚・兰伯特 再见,布兰琪
Good-bye, Julia Rainbird! Good-bye, Blanche.
再见
[Softly] Good-bye.
布兰琪夫人,你没事吧?
[Moans] Madame Blanche! Are you all right?
噢,这是…
Oh. It was... [Clears Throat, Noisily]
这到底是怎么回事?
What in the world's been going on here?
我觉得我好像做了什么事
I feel as though I've been properly done over.
你不记得发生什么了?
Don't you remember what happened? Mm-mm.
不记得细节了,布兰琪女士 只有大略,你应该知道我的意思
Not the details, Miss Rainbird, only the gist, if you know what I mean.
我以为你会告诉我一些要点
Suppose you give me the gist of it. [Blows Nose]
喔,我不知道…
Oh well, I wonder... [Gasps]
我能麻烦你弄点什么喝的…
Could I trouble you for a sip of something? Ju-Just...
噢,当然,你要喝什么?
Oh, of course. What would you like?
噢,随便给我一点混合的…
Oh, a double shot of anyth...
- 来点雪莉酒或许比较好 - 噢,是的,没问题
- A spot of that sherry might be nice. - Oh, yes. Of course.
谢谢
[Sniffles] Thank you.
- 现在,请告诉我还记得的招魂内容 - 说个大概?
- Now, tell me what you remember of the seance. - In a nutshell?
拜托了
Please.
嗯…
Well... [Clears Throat]
大约40年前,你安排…
About 40 years ago, you arranged to have...
把你妹妹的小婴儿送给了别人
your sister Harriet's baby given away without a trace.
如今你总是做噩梦 你困惑的良心告诉你
And now your bad dreams and troubled conscience tell you...
必须去找到长大了的小孩 并带他回家
to find the grown-up person, take him into the family...
给予他财富
and bestow your wealth on him.
- 很好 - 谢谢
Excellent. Thank you.
但我为什么 要强迫我妹妹把小孩送人?
And why did I force my sister to give the child away?
我想,那个小孩可能是…私生子 兰伯特女士
I guess the kid was a... illegitimate, Miss Rainbird.
我不希望你以为我是个清教徒 布兰琪夫人
I don't want you to think me a puritan, Madame Blanche.
但是,40年前,未婚母亲
But 40 years ago, an unmarried mother...
并不像现在这么普遍
was not the commonplace it is nowadays.
尤其是在我们这样的家族
And in a family like ours,
不得不牺牲一切代价来掩盖丑闻
a scandal had to be covered up at all costs.
我明白
I understand.
我必须保持传统
And I'm still sufficiently old-fashioned,
并维护兰伯特家的名声
and sufficiently protective of the Rainbird name,
寻找失踪的继承人时…
to want to seek the missing heir...
必须以私人并秘密的方式进行
in a private and secret fashion,
而不是去找侦探社
rather than go to detective agencies...
或是登报寻人
and put notices in the newspapers.
这是个明智的决定 兰伯特女士
A most wise decision, Miss Rainbird.
那么,现在 我们找到了必须请你帮忙的理由
Well, now, suppose we get to the reason...
for my sending for you.
我已经78岁了
I'm 78 years of age.
我希望能带着一颗平静的心 跨进棺材
I would like to go to my grave with a quiet conscience.
特别是当我知道唯一的继承人 就在外面的某个地方
Particularly as I know that my only heir is out there somewhere,
是我的行为 剥夺了他兰伯特的姓氏
deprived by my acts of his true Rainbird name.
你能用你的力量帮助我吗?
Will you help me with your powers?
如果你是诚心的,我可以
If in your heart you believe that I can,
我有责任让我们共同去尝试 兰伯特女士
then I owe it to both of us to try, Miss Rainbird.
不,我太老了,做不到了
No, I'm too old for trying.
我只来得及去看到结果
I've only time enough left for results!
帮我找到他,布兰琪夫人 用你的精神力量,还有你的亨利
Find him for me, Madame Blanche. Use your spirit-control, your "Henry."
透过我的妹妹
Get through to my sister.
找到她的儿子 查出他是谁,无论他的身分
Find her son, whoever he is, wherever he is,
我会付给你一万美元
and I'll pay you $10,000.
一万…
Te...
如果你是真心的,兰伯特女士
Only if you genuinely wish to, Miss Rainbird.
但是不要认为这些钱是付给了我
But let's not think of this as a payment to me.
因为我很有爱心
There are many causes dear to my heart,
世上所有的慈善机构都需要它
which need all the charity the world can spare.
你不知道它让一个女人多么振奋 我的财富
You've no idea how refreshing it is for a woman of my wealth...
找个人只需要用到这么一点点钱
to find someone who has so little use for money.
谢谢
Thank you.
那么,我想我们已经谈妥了
[Sighs] Well, now, I regard our arrangement as completed.
我的睡觉时间到了
I... It's my bedtime.
我必须向你这位 令人愉快的客人告别了
I must take leave of your delightful company.
对我来说这是一个难忘的夜晚 兰伯特女士
This has been a most memorable evening for me, Miss Rainbird.
你让钱发挥了更大的价值
See to it that you make it a rewarding one.
你让自己反覆的陷入险境
At the risk of repeating myself,
我希望你不要忘记…
I hope you will not forget...
没有人,绝对没有任何人 能知道我们的寻找行动
that nobody, absolutely no one,
should know of our search.
兰伯特家的名声必须受到保护
The Rainbird name must be protected.
我保证守口如瓶
My jaw is locked.
一言为定,再见了 感谢你的光临
On that note, I will say good-bye, and thank you for coming.
事情怎么样了?
So, how'd it go?
我不知道,扮演亨利 简直是在谋杀我的喉咙
I don't know. Having to do Henry is murder on my throat.
- 谋杀 - 是,是,我明白
- Murder. - Yeah, yeah. I know.
- 那事情怎么样了? - 她上钩了,就等着被拉上来
- So how did it go? - She's hooked, waiting to be pulled in.
另一条价值25元的沙丁鱼?
Another one of your $25 sardines?
不,这是条大鱼,乔治 一条大鲸鱼
No. This is a big one, George. A great big whale.
哦,快点,告诉我
Well, come on. Give.
把你的眼睛留在路上,别催我
Keep your eyes on the road. Don't rush me.
好的,布兰琪
[Sighs] Okay, Blanchie.
洗耳恭听
Start way up at the top.
嗯,就像收听ABC广播一样简单 亨利来找我,来自天上
Well, it was as simple as A-B-C. Henry came to me from the Upper Brightness,
低声对我说 "这位女士长期有睡眠的困扰"
whispered to me, "This womars been having sleep problems."
之后就顺其自然,按照逻辑
From there on, things followed naturally, logically.
啊哈,我一次又帮了你大忙啊 亲爱的?
Aha! So I came through for you again, didn't I, darlin?
不,你在说什么,乔治?
No. What are you talking about, George?
你是什么意思,我说了什么?
What do you mean, what am I talking about?
你他妈的知道我在说什么
You know damn well what I'm talking about.
所有的资讯 是我向当地的药剂师挖来的…
All that information that I dug up by gabbir to the local druggist...
关于她被失眠搞得快发疯…
about how she was drivir him crazy...
试图没有处方购买安眠药
tryir to get sleeping pills without a prescription!
这本来对我非常非常有用
That could have been very, very useful to me.
为什么你没告诉我这些事?
Why didn't you tell me about that?
你什么意思? 我没告诉你? 你他妈的知道我告诉过你
What do you mean, why didn't I tell you? I told you. You know damn well I told you.
不,你总是以为你告诉过我事情 但其实你忘了
No, you always think you tell me things, and you forget to.
我必须跨越天堂与地狱 去和亨利沟通
I have to go through heaven and hell, the Great Beyond, with Henry.
亨利,听好,是我
Henry, my ass. It was me.
总是我
It's always me.
如果没有我的调查 你这通灵人不过是个干腊肠
Without my research, you're about as psychic as a dry salami.
龌龊,龌龊,龌龊
[Sighs] Nasty. Nasty, nasty.
我已经厌烦了当你的水晶球
I'm sick and tired of having you hang me by the crystal balls.
顾好你自己的水晶球吧,乔治
Leave your crystal balls out of this, George.
不,别谈亨利了 把废话留给你的客户吧
No, let's leave Henry out of this and keep the bullshit for your customers.
你嫉妒他,是吗?
You're jealous of him, aren't you?
喔,拜托,布兰琪
Oh, please, Blanche.
我喜欢你的嫉妒 这是你这驾驶的臭味
I like your jealousy. It's your driving that stinks.
嘿,听着,我偶尔也是个演员 不是计程车司机
Hey, look. I happen to be an actor, not a cab driver.
我当然能扮演司机 但我相信地狱不需要一位驾驶
I can play cab drivers, but I sure as hell don't have to drive like one.
哦,直到我赚到 朱莉亚・兰伯特这一票以前
Well, until I can collect from Julia Rainbird,
恐怕你需要 继续扮演好计程车司机
I'm afraid you're gonna have to go on playing a cab driver.
我们俩都不希望饿死
Neither of us seems to be very fond of starving to death.
哦,我们该如何干这票 这条兰伯特鲸鱼能喷出多少钱?
Well, how are we supposed to collect? How much is this Rainbird whale gonna spout up?
你要继续扮演好私家侦探
Also, you're gonna have to go on playing a private eye.
上帝,不! 我已经演够了私家侦探
Christ, no! I've had it playing private eyes.
上帝,是的! 乔治
Christ, yes! Now, George.
停止亵渎吧
Stop blaspheming.
你想要诅咒十张大钞?
You wanna put the curse on ten big ones?
等一等,布兰琪
Now, wait a minute, Blanche.
- 你说十张大钞? - 嗯哼
- Did you say ten big ones? - Mm-hmm.
- 一万? - 嗯哼
- Ten thousand? - Mm-hmm.
- 美元? - 美元,乔治!
- Dollars? - Dollars, George!
现在,布兰琪,你想想…
[Chuckles] Now, Blanche, you got any idea...
我们能如何花这一万美元?
what you and I could do with ten grand?
嗯哼,我们甚至可以结婚
Mm-hmm. We could even get married.
为什么你总是要扫兴呢?
What are you always a wet blanket for?
哈,你太夸奖我了
[Laughs] Oh, you flatter me so.
那么,怎么做? 我们该做什么?
Well, what's the deal? What do we have to do?
我晚点会在床上告诉你的
I'll tell you about it in bed, afterwards.
噢,拜托,布兰琪,给我一点暗示
Aw, come on, Blanche. Give me a hint.
只是一点…前戏
Just a little... [Chuckles] Fore play.
好吧,找一个人,就这样
All right. Find one man. That's all.
哦,我们做过更糟糕的事 他叫什么名字?
Well, we've had to do worse than that. What's his name?
呃…没有人知道
Hmm. Ah... nobody knows.
- 那么,他是谁? - 好问题,没有人知道
- Well, who is he? - That's a problem. Nobody knows.
- 他在哪里? - 没有人知道
- [Laughs] Where is he? - Nobody knows.
喔,别说笑了,你的意思是 都没有人知道,布兰琪?
Well, for chrissake! You mean, nobody knows, Blanche?
没有人知道他的名字 他在哪里,或者他是谁?
Nobody knows his name, or where he is, or who he is?
嘿,乔治,别叫了
Well, George, stop yelling.
有个人可能会知道
There's a possibility of one person who might have known.
- 哦,是谁? - 朱莉亚・兰伯特没有对我提到他
- Well, who's that? - Julia Rainbird didn't mention him to me.
幸运的是 她的朋友爱达・库克森跟我说了
Fortunately, her friend Ida Cookson did.
- 哦,那是谁? - 兰伯特的私人司机
- Well, who is it? - The Rainbird family chauffeur.
哦,你总算说出了一条正道
[Sighs] Well, now you're talkir. Now we're on our way.
麻烦的是…呃…
Trouble is... Well,
他已经死了25年
he's been dead for 25 years.
喔,别再说笑了,布兰琪…
Oh, for chrissake, Blanche...
喔,不不不,别紧张,乔治
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, don't start to fret, George,
否则今晚我们在水床上 将会失去乐趣
or our water bed will be no fun at all tonight.
做为一个演员,你应该知道 烦躁会毁了演出的
As an actor, you should know fretting will ruin a performance.
你该不会是在担心 我今晚的表现吧
You're not gonna have to worry about my performance tonight.
事实上,今天晚上
As a matter of fact, uh, on this very evening,
你会想要起立鼓掌的
you're gonna see a standing ovation.
她在这里,不,不是男的 是个女人
She's here. No, not a man. It's a woman.
好的,跟我来
Right. Follow me.
只要维克多・康斯坦丁 还在你手上,我们就不能动你
As long as you've got Victor Constantine, we can't touch you.
所以,你不如把那东西放下吧
So you might as well put that thing away.
你一直称自己为"交易人" 因此我们以为你是一个男人
[Man #1] You've been calling yourself"The Trader," so we thought you were a man.
我认为我们也应该得到一些保证 确认肉票仍然活着
[Man #2] I think we deserve some assurance that the victim is still alive.
按照你的指示 无线电已经从直升机上移除
[Man #1] All radios have been removed from the helicopter, as you instructed.
"康斯坦丁先生正在昏睡当中 只要等安眠药药效退去就会醒来"
"Mr. Constantine will be unconscious but in perfect condition when picked up.
Just let him sleep the drug off."
好吧,警长,开灯
All right, Sergeant, turn on the lights.
- 别逞英雄 - 是的,先生
- Don't try and be a hero. - Yes, sir.
好,我们已经尽了我们的部分
Well, we've done our part.
我们要去哪?
Where are we going?
别发生任何该死的错误
Not one goddamn mistake.
还要飞多远?
How far are we going?
你运气真好 他们还愿意为肉票付出
It's lucky for you they've still got the victim.
更重要的是我把你扔下去 这件事没发生在你身上
I'd like nothing better than to toss you right out of this thing on your head.
当然,这趟小旅行是你预订的 不是吗?
You sure have this little trip mapped out, don't you?
我打赌,那东西甚至没装子弹
I bet that thing isn't even loaded.
高尔夫球场?
Golf course, huh?
耀眼,非常完美
Brilliant. Absolutely perfect.
我的脚快断了 这该死的六英几吒鞋
My feet are killing me. These damn six-inch heels.
我恰巧喜欢高挑的女人
I happen to like tall women.
每个人都喜欢高挑的女人
Everybody likes tall women.
事实上,每个人都在寻找 高挑的女人
In fact, everyone's going to be looking for a tall woman.
但总是不尽如人意
Aside from complaining a lot,
你最近都在做些什么?
what have you been doing with yourself lately?
噢,没什么,抱赎金啦 诸如此类的事情
Oh, nothing much. Picking up a ransom, that sort of thing.
你有看到任何 我们不知道的人吗?
Did you see anyone, uh, we know?
有两个看来是警察 另外第三个绝对是FBI
Two men who look like police and a third who just had to be F.B.I.
最常和你打交道的人
You mix with the nicest people.
家常便饭
Beats housework.
- 你有对他们说什么? - 一个声音也没发出
- Did you say anything to them? - Not a syllable.
你看吧,亲爱的
Now, you see, honey?
我说过你可以学着缄默 只要你去尝试
I told you you could learn to keep your mouth shut, if you tried.
瞧瞧是谁在这里?
Look who's here.
嗯,有没有人看到一位身材高挑的 金发美女,刚才她还在这里
Mm. Has anyone seen a tall, blonde woman around here lately?
喔,走掉了,有谁会需要她?
Gone, poof! Who needs her?
我要,至少多留点时间给我吧
I do. At least one more time.
好了,亲爱的
Let me put that there, darlin.
康斯坦丁先生给我们 留了一点葡萄酒
Mr. Constantine has left us some wine.
我不认为他喜欢进口的东西
I don't think he likes the imported stuff.
嗯…还有我的牛肉干酪
Uh... It was probably my veal parmesan.
- 我想我煮得太烂了 - 他喜欢在餐厅吃东西,就这样
- I'm afraid I overcooked it. - He likes eating in a room with a view, that's all.
你知道,有钱人很挑剔的
You know how fussy rich people are.
别忘了洗干净
Don't forget to empty that out.
你不觉得洗马桶 有损宝石收藏家的尊严吗?
Don't you think emptying a chemical toilet...
is below the dignity of a jewel collector?
- 真是罪恶的工作啊,亚瑟 - 我明天再做
- The wages of sin, Arthur. - I'll do it tomorrow.
不能拖到明天…
Never put off till tomorrow...
- 或是你今晚也可以先略过 - 婊子
- what you can empty out tonight. - Bitch.
亚瑟,阿姆斯特丹是怎样的地方?
Arthur, what's Amsterdam like?
喔,大量的运河
Oh, lots of canals.
很多干瘪的老头…
Lots of wizened old men...
坐在大石头上 以锐利的目光盯着年轻人
with sharp eyes, sitting around cutting big stones into little ones.
你会看到的
You'll see.
我不知道什么是影响我 今晚我浑身感到不舒服
I don't know what's come over me tonight. I'm tingling all over.
我告诉过你危险的,不是吗?
I told you about danger, didn't I?
首先,它使你生病
First it makes you sick.
当你平安度过,它又让你非常…
Then, when you get through it, it makes you very,
非常热爱
very loving.
- 亲爱的,这… - 嗯?
- Darling, is it... - Hmm?
这太过容易了,让人害怕
It was all too easy. It's frightening.
出色的计划
[Sighs] Brilliant planning.
他们没有任何线索可以追踪
They don't have a single lead to follow.
我们对他用的麻药有效吗?
What about the ketamine we stuck him with?
哦,如果沃格尔医生六个月前 拔我的臼齿时有效
Well, if Doctor Vogel didn't miss it six months ago when I had my wisdom tooth out,
现在对他一样有效吧
he's not gonna miss it now.
不要在这里浪费时间了 我们上床吧
Don't finish up in there. Let's go to bed.
- 累了吗? - 嗯,全身酸痛
- Tired? - Mm-mm. Tingling all over.
为什么我会让你占有这一切?
How'd I ever let you get me into all this?
我想我爱上了你 因为我需要一些稳定
I thought I fell in love with you because I needed some stability.
哦,我猜只是你的性格不好
Well, I guess you're just a bad judge of character.
- 你把到手的钻石放在哪? - 大家都看得到的地方
- Where'd you put the diamond, dear? - Where everyone can see it.
- 你才没有 - 我有
- You didn't. - I did.
- 你要告诉我在哪里吗? - 你得先折磨我
- Are you gonna tell me where? - You'll have to torture me first.
喔,我正打算呢
Oh! [Giggling] I intend to.
就在几分钟后
In a few minutes.
我已经够尊重FBI和督察局了
Now, with all due respect to the F.B.I. And the Bureau of Inspectors,
我没有时间玩游戏
I have no time to play games.
不要忘记,先生们 我已经强烈的想离开这个办公桌
Now, lest we forget, gentlemen, I have been away from this desk forcibly.
我还有许多工作赶着做
I've got a lot of work to catch up on.
这该死的事情 我们还要谈多少回?
Now, how many more times we gonna go through this goddamn thing?
直到我们找到线索为止 康斯坦丁先生
Until we come up with something, Mr. Constantine.
这种解决绑架的方法真是地狱
That's a hell of a way to solve a kidnapping.
康斯坦丁先生,你要知道 你不是第一个受害者,还有其他人
Mr. Constantine, you're not the first victim, you know. There have been others.
好了,好了,但是从我这里 你们也得不到线索的
All right, all right. But from me, you'll learn absolutely nothing.
- 你永远不会知道 - 我知道
- You never know. - I know.
好吧,弗伊
All right. Floyd?
现在,从地下停车场说起
Now. The underground garage.
- 停满了车 - 声音呢?
- Full of cars. - Sounds?
- 有个人在我身后 - 是男人还是女人?
- People, behind me. - Was it a man, or was it a woman?
- 我不知道 - 男人还是女人?
- I don't know. - Man or woman?
- 男人 - 然后呢?
- Man. - Then what?
就在我正要转身时 我的肩膀一阵刺痛
[Grunts] It was a prick in my shoulder. I started to turn.
接着,我在一个房间里醒来
Eh...And I woke up in a room.
是的,你有听到什么吗? 屋内或屋外的声音?
[Floyd] Yes, and what did you hear? Inside or outside?
房间是隔音的
The room was soundproofed.
我什么都听不到 除了扬声器里传来空洞的声音
I never heard anything except a disembodied voice of a loudspeaker.
- 描述一下 - 但我已经说过了
- Describe it. - But I've already done that.
再说一次!
Again!
是一个男人的声音,没有口音
It was the voice of a man, no accent.
- 电子变声过,无法辨识 - 有几个人在那里?
- Doctored up electronically. Unrecognizable. - How many of them were there?
两个,一男一女
Two. A man and a woman.
- 你为什么这么说? - 因为只有微弱的光线照射下来
- Why do you say that? - Because the faintest light filtered down from above.
不足以给我机会看看他们是谁
But not enough to give me a chance to see who they were.
- 那么是谁煮饭? - 她煮的
- Yes, and who did the cooking? - She did.
- 为什么? - 因为男人不会费心思…
- Why? - Because a man would not bother to put the parsley...
在鱼排上放香芹,这就是原因
on the filet of sole, that's why.
- 她多大年纪? - 喔,拜托
- How old is she? - Come on, now. Please.
- 她多大年纪? - 25
- How old is she? - Twenty-five.
- 为什么? - 为什么?
- Why? - Why?
如果像我这样年龄的男人 要被一个女人绑架
Because if a man my age is gonna get kidnapped by a woman,
他希望她有25岁,这就是原因
he wants her to be 25, that's why.
- 描述一下你如何被释放 - 释放…
- Describe your return. - The return.
那空洞的声音叫我坐下来 并背对着门
The disembodied voice tells me to sit with my back to the door.
灯光熄灭,门打开,他们走了进来
The light goes out, the door opens, they both come in.
我感到左手臂一阵刺痛
I feel a prick in my left arm.
接下来我只知道 我在医院的病床上醒来
The next thing I know, I wake up in that hospital bed...
你就坐在那里,开始问东问西的
with you sitting there, thinking up questions!
谢谢,康斯坦丁先生 你做得很好
Thank you, Mr. Constantine. You're doing great.
- 这就是你的感想 - 好,让我们重头开始
- That's what you think. - All right, let's start all over again.
噢,妈的!
Aw, shit!
亨利,为什么你面带微笑?
[Blanche] Why, Henry, you have such a beaming smile on your face.
我微笑是因为我很高兴,布兰琪
[Blanche Playing Henry] I smile because I'm happy, Blanche.
能透过你,布兰琪 传达讯息给你朋友,爱达・库克森
It comes through you, Blanche, from your friend, Ida Cookson.
我是她的向导,亨利
[In Blanche's Voice] I'm her guide, Henry.
只有在不被否认的时候 才能称为真正的友谊
Friendship can be claimed only when it cannot be denied.
告诉爱达・库克森 我们在这里都很感谢…
[In Henry's Voice] Tell Ida Cookson we're all thankful here...
她温暖而宁静的心灵
for the warm tranquility in her heart.
因为她信任你,使得这更加温暖
It will grow even warmer as she trusts in you,
向你倾诉,没有对你保留秘密…
and confides in you, and holds back no secrets from you...
无论是对她自己 或是她的亲密朋友
be they her own, or those of her intimate friends.
你听到了吗? 库克森夫人
[Blanche's Voice] Did you hear that, Mrs. Cookson?
是的,布兰琪夫人
[Mrs. Cookson] Yes, Madame Blanche.
亨利,我需要你 帮我们寻找沃尔特
[Blanche] Henry, I want you to seek Walter for us now.
透过善意的寻找,直到…
Search through to the Double Strand of Kindness, until...
我的朋友爱达・库克森 能加入这爱的交流
my friend Ida Cookson is joined in loving communication...
与她亲爱的丈夫沟通
with her dear, departed husband.
我试试看,布兰琪
[In Henry's Voice] I will try, Blanche.
但是首先,必须让迷雾消散 并揭起薄纱
But first, the mist must part a little, and the veil must rise...
让光线指引我们道路
to let in the light that will show us the path.
我准备好了,亨利
[In Blanche's Voice] Ah, I'm ready now, Henry.
准备,准备好了跟随你 无论你要我去哪儿
Ready! Ready to follow you, wherever you want me to go.
哪里? 你要带我到哪里,亨利?
Where? Where are you taking me, Henry?
是的,是的,我看到了
[Gasps] Yes, yes, yes! I see.
我看到你在向我招手
I see your hand beckoning to me. [Laughing]
喔,多么迷人的花园啊,亨利
Oh, what a lovely garden, Henry.
我…我,喔!
My, my. Oh!
那是…那是一尊雕像吗?
Is that... Is that a statue there?
噢,那是沃尔特站在喷泉旁边吗?
Oh! Could this be Walter standing beside the fountain?
- 你怎么能这样对我? - 我需要你的车钥匙…
[Whispering] - How can you do this to me? - I need your car keys.
- 我赶时间 - 喔!
- I'm in a hurry. - Oh!
你知道打断我的思绪 会造成什么损害吗?
Do you realize what damage you can do my psyche, breaking in this way?
只要给我你的钥匙,我赶时间
Just give me your keys. I need 'em.
是的,亨利! 要干嘛?
[Shouting] Yes, Henry! [Whispering] What for?
我找到兰伯特司机的女儿了
I've located the daughter of the Rainbird chauffeur.
- 我这计程车司机却去不了 - 喔!
- And I'm not going as a cab driver. - [Shouting] Oh!
- 你说我应该做的,我却没有车? - 我才不在乎你做什么
- What am I supposed to do without my car? - I don't care what you do.
- 我开计程车,只要给我钥匙 - 树在摇动!
- Take a taxi. Just give me the keys. - The trees are swaying!
枝叶分开了!
And the branches part!
但那儿一个人也没有! 在这里
But there's no one there! [Whispering] Here.
我看到影子消失了! 空气越来越冷!
I see shadows falling! The air is getting cold!
光线变暗了,再见,亨利!
The brightness... dims. Good-bye, Henry!
喔!
Oh! [Chimes Tinkling]
你找到沃尔特了?
[Gasps] Did you find Walter?
- 在哪里? - 在厨房里啊
- Where? - In the kitchen.
没错
I did.
我不知道能不能和你谈几分钟 海妮根女士?
I wonder if I could speak to you for a couple minutes, Mrs. Hannagan.
当然,我们认识吗?
Why, sure. Do we know each other?
不,我叫法兰克・麦克布莱 弗格森和麦克布莱律师事务所的
No, I'm Frank McBride, of the law firm of Ferguson, Ferguson & McBride,
我只是想知道,如果你不介意 回答一些关于你背景的问题
and I just wondered if you would mind...
answering a couple questions about your background.
- 我的背景? - 嗯
My background? Mm-hmm.
就像洗碗水一样无趣
[Chuckles] Dull as dishwater.
我的意思是 你为什么会想知道这个?
I mean, what in the world would you be wanting with that?
呃,这样说吧,嗯…
Well, let's just say that the, uh,
我对那些讯息感兴趣 是因为值不少钱
information that I'm interested in could be won'th a great deal of money.
哦,是吗? 给谁?
- Oh, yeah? To who? - Mm-hmm.
嗯,我们只要花一点点时间 问几个愉快的小问题,如果你不介意
Well, we'll get around to that pleasant little subject in a minute, if you don't mind.
- 好吧 - 太好了
- Okay. - Oh, swell.
现在,我们从头开始吧?
Now, why don't we just start at the beginning?
- 你的父母呢? - 喔,他们都过世了,蒙主宠召
- Your parents. - Oh, they're both dead. God rest 'em.
- 你的父亲是一名司机,对吧? - 你怎么知道?
Your father was a chauffeur, though, right? How did you know that?
他是兰伯特家族的司机
[Chuckles] He was a chauffeur for the Rainbird family.
又说对了! 你像是个冥界的侦探 麦克布莱先生
Right again! You'd be a hell of a detective, Mr. McBride.
这我可就不知道了,亲爱的
[Chuckles] I don't know about that, my dear.
这段时间,你还记不记得有谁…
Now, during this period of time, though, can you remember anybody, uh,
是你父亲的亲密朋友?
being a close friend of your father's?
嗯,是有一个人 很久以前了,当时我还在读书
Uh, there was a man. It was away back when I was in school.
那人经常和我父亲一起喝啤酒
Uh, there was this guy that my father used to drink beer with...
并一起到村里打撞球
and shoot pool with down in the village.
这哈利・休奎奇 和他太太莎蒂开了一间家禽店
This Harry Shoebridge had a poultry shop with his wife, Sadie.
休奎奇
[Chuckles] Shoebridge.
是啊,他的生意一直很差
Yeah. His business was always lousy,
即使在景气好的时候
even when times were good.
她曾经流产过…
And she used to have miscarriages...
就像其他女人一样不再过生日
like other women have birthdays.
后来,他们放弃并搬走了
Well, they stopped trying, and they moved away...
搬到巴洛溪去 并收养了一个小孩,我想
to Barlow Creek, and, uh, adopted a kid, I think.
- 男孩吗? - 是啊,一个婴儿
A boy? Yeah. An infant.
但是,你知道的,我不太确定
But, you know, I'm not so sure.
我…记忆有些模糊,嗯…
I... It's all kind of hazy, an-and, uh,
我试着回想…
I keep connecting it with...
嗯,我记得有一晚
[Bell Dinging] Well, I remember this night...
我父亲从休奎奇那里 一个人开车回家
with my Dad driving over there...
to the Shoebridge's all alone, and then getting in...
然后和我妈妈大吵了一架 因为他回到家时已经凌晨四点了
a big fight with Ma because he'd come home at 4:00 A.M.,
且他不告诉她 他到底去做了些什么
and he wouldn't tell her what he was doing or something.
现在,我父亲过世了 愿上帝保佑他的灵魂安息
Now, after my dad passed away... God rest his soul...
我妈妈非常痛恨休奎奇
my ma was damn mad at the Shoebridge's,
因为他们一直没有来参加葬礼
because they never showed up at the funeral.
- 后来,她发现了原因 - 为什么?
- Then she found out why. - Why?
就在一年前 他们参加了自己的葬礼
A year earlier, they'd gone to their own funeral.
- 死了? - 嗯
- Dead? - Mm-hmm.
- 他们和房子一起烧死了 - 那么,小孩怎么了?
- Their house burned down with them in it. - Well, what about the son?
海妮根女士! 你没看到有顾客吗?
Mrs. Hannagan! Can't you see that there are customers?
- 噢,好的,我马上过去 - 她马上过去,夫人
- Oh, yes. Yes. I'll be right there. - She'll be right there, ma'am.
嗯,听着,麦克布莱先生
Uh-Uh, look, um, Mr. McBride,
- 事情差不多就这样了 - 海妮根女士
- about all this being won'th something... - Mrs. Hannagan!
- 好的 - 等一下
[Sighs] - Yeah. - Wait a second.
我到哪里才能找到 休奎奇的儿子?
This Shoebridge son... where do I look for him?
嗯,到巴洛溪公墓试试吧
Well, try the Barlow Creek Cemetery.
- 什么意思,到公墓? - 嗯,我不确定,但我认为他死了
- What do you mean, the cemetery? - Well, I'm not sure, but I think he's dead, too.
抱歉!
Sorry!
(哈利・休奎奇、莎蒂・休奎奇)
(艾迪・休奎奇)
死胡同,布兰琪
[Shovel Scraping] Dead end, Blanche.
早就埋葬了
Dead and buried.
- 我是管理人,能为你做什么吗? - 我是这家庭的朋友
- Caretaker. Do somethir for you? - I'm a friend of the family.
什么都没留下,这差事糟透了
None left. Bad business, that.
你是指大火吗?
You mean the fire?
我不喜欢他们同时被埋葬
Never liked them multiple funerals.
太多工作都挤在同一时间
Too much work involved, all at one time.
他们是一起死的 但他们没有埋在一起
They died together, yet they're not...
buried together in the same hole.
为什么?
How come?
我怎么知道
Search me.
瞧这里
Here. Look.
1950年过世
Died in 1950. Died 1950.
这两个死亡日期相同
Both died the same date.
旧石碑
Old stone.
而这个是新的石碑
This is practically new stone.
- 真是聪明人 - 怎么? 被我发现什么了?
- Smart fellow, ain't ya? - Why? Have I stumbled on to something?
哦,很高兴认识你
Well, nice meetir ya.
我该回去干活了 明天在这儿还有份工作
Better get back to my work. I got a job comir in here tomorrow.
把那该死的东西关小,玛西洛
Turn that damn thing down, Marcella.
我甚至听不到自己的说话声
Can't even hear myself think. [Fades]
你想我怎么可能 记得那么久以前的事情?
How do you expect me to remember anything that far back?
我必须要翻阅我的旧档案 来找资料才行
I'd have to go through my old files for that kind of information.
嗯,威勒先生,我不喜欢坚持…
Well, Mr. Wheeler, I hate to insist...
你知道吗? 麦克布莱先生
[Chiseling, Music Continue] You know something, Mr. McBride?
你们律师全都一样
You lawyers are all alike.
麻烦,麻烦,麻烦
Trouble, trouble, trouble.
来吧,我可没有整天的时间
Well, come on. I don't have all day.
你说的那一家是哪一年死的?
What year did you say the family died?
嗯…1950年
Uh, 1950.
几月?
[Groans] What month?
- 这我可帮不了你 - 休奎奇,休奎…
Ah, I can't help you there.
- 我能坐下吗? - 好,请便
- Shoebridge. Shoebri... - Can I sit down? - Yeah, go ahead.
休奎奇,休奎奇
Shoebridge. Shoebridge.
喔,在这儿 "休奎奇,哈利和莎蒂"
Oh, here it is. "Shoebridge: Harry and Sadie.
"大型大理石,28号"
"Large marble. Model 28.
"全额支付,检索编号93"
"Paid in full. Check number 93.
"第一教堂末世圣徒,巴洛溪"
First Church of Latter Day Saints, Barlow Creek."
那儿子呢?
What about the son?
- 艾迪・休奎奇,他们的儿子 - 艾迪?
- Edward Shoebridge. He's their son. - Edward?
- 是的 - 好…不
- Yeah. - Okay. Nope.
- 没有 - 什么意思,没有?
- Nothing. - What do you mean, nothing?
肯定有,或许他比较晚来
There's gotta be something. Maybe it came later.
等等,你是说艾迪・休奎奇 他的墓碑? 是的,他比较晚来
Wait a minute. You're talking about Eddie Shoebridge.
His headstone? Yeah, that did come later. [Coughs]
我想是,嗯…65号
I think in, uh, '65.
是的,我记得那孩子
Sure, I remember that kid.
他在这里太受欢迎 有人说是他自己放的火
He wasrt too popular around here. Some say he set that fire himself...
为了摆脱他的家人然后消失
to get rid of his family, and then disappeared...
使他看起来 像是也在大火中丧生
to make it look like he died in the fire too.
- 他们从来没发现他的尸体 - 你是说没有尸体在他的坟墓中?
- They never did find his body. - You mean, there's no body in that grave?
嗯,我记得 这就是为什么当地的牧师…
Well, as I recollect, that's why the local parson...
没有为艾迪做任何事的原因
wouldn't say any services for Eddie.
没有死亡证明吗?
Well, [Coughs] Wasrt there a death certificate?
我不知道,我也不需要知道
I wouldn't know about that. And I don't need to know.
我只是个生意人,麦克布莱先生
I'm just a businessman, Mr. McBride.
啊,在这儿
- [Sighs] - Ah, here it is.
"艾迪・休奎奇,特级花岗岩"
"Edward Shoebridge. Granite special.
"11月12日订制"
"Ordered, November 12.
"1965年11月18日支付"
"Paid for, November 18, 1965.
"395美元"
$395."
有趣的是,他以现金支付
Now, that's funny. It's paid in cash.
- 他们通常不会这样做 - 那是谁?
- They don't usually do that. - Who was it?
我不知道,麦克布莱先生
I don't know, Mr. McBride.
我猜他不想让人知道他的名字
I guess he didn't want his name known.
什么意思"他"?
Well, what do you mean, he?
- 你刚才说"他" - 我有说吗?
- You just said he. - I did, didn't I?
哦,你知道的 我依稀记得好像…是个男人
Well, you know, I seem to sort of remember...
that it was a man.
对了,年轻小伙子
Yeah. A young fella.
微秃,我猜他20多岁
Slightly bald. I'd say in his late twenties.
你有没有再见到他,嗯… 安置墓碑的时候?
And did you see him again when you, uh...
[Scratches Paper] Put in the headstone?
我们并没有这样做 是他自己来把墓碑带走的
We didn't do that. He came by and picked it up himself.
对,我想起来了,用一辆拖车
Yes, I remember now. In one of those tow trucks.
- 你知道,那种拖车库的? - 我知道
- You know, the kind that garages use? - Gotcha.
(出生死亡登记处)
[Typing, Chattering]
不,这里没有 艾迪・休奎奇的死亡证明
No, there is no death certificate here for Edward Shoebridge,
只有哈利・休奎奇和 莎蒂・休奎奇的
only Harry J. Shoebridge and Sadie L. Shoebridge.
就只有这样?
That's all you have?
哦,这里还有
Well, there is this.
似乎曾有人为艾迪・休奎奇 申请死亡证明书
It appears to be an application for a death certificate...
日期是1965年11月4日
for one Edward Shoebridge, dated November 4, 1965.
"由于申请人无提供任何死亡证据"
"Inasmuch as applicant could furnish no proof of death...
"当事人的尸体一直未被寻获"
"for party whose body had never been found,
"没有提供医疗死亡证明书"
"and who could supply no medical death certificate,
"亦没有法医检验,该申请被拒绝"
"and nothing from the coroner's office, the application was denied.
"申请人接获通知后可到法院诉讼"
"Applicant, when informed he could file a petition for court action,
"但拒绝了这项建议"
declined the suggestion."
有说申请人是谁吗?
Does it say who the applicant was?
有,"申请人乔森・马洛尼"
Yes. "Request was made by Joseph P. Maloney,
"巴洛溪426大街"
426 Main Street, Barlow Creek."
- 很好,谢谢你 - 不客气
- Attagirl. Thank you. - You're welcome.
(J・马洛尼)
- 加满? - 麻烦你
- Fill 'er up? - Please.
- 你要检查引擎吗? - 如果你可以,麻烦你
- You want to check under the hood? - If you would, please.
- 小心火柴 - 喔,好的
- Better be careful with those matches. - Oh. Right.
抱歉
Sorry.
- 这店是你开的? - 是啊
This your place? [Dinging] Yeah.
那你一定就是"J・马洛尼"
Then you must be, uh, "J. Maloney."
告诉我,这是代表,嗯… 约翰・马洛尼?
Tell me, does that stand for, uh, John orJim? [Dinging]
- 乔森 - 是的
- Joe. - Right.
一切正常
[Pumping Stops] Everything's okay.
有趣,嗯…你几乎不需要任何油
Funny, uh, you didn't hardly need any gas.
不需要加油… 我猜你来这里不是为了车,先生?
Didrt need no oil... Guess you didn't come here for the car, huh, mister?
你能帮我擦一下挡风玻璃吗?
Could you get my windshield, please?
没问题
Don't worry.
你知道一个叫做 艾迪・休奎奇的人吗?
You wouldn't happen to know a guy by the name of Edward Shoebridge, would ya?
以前住在这一边
Used to live around here.
这名字我没印象
Name don't ring no bell with me.
为什么你要问这个 嗯,他叫什么…休奎奇?
What would you be wantir with this, uh, what's his name, uh, Shoebridge?
是啊,法律问题
Yeah. Legal matter.
- 你是律师? - 对
- You a lawyer? - Yeah. [Coughs]
我叫麦克布莱 法兰克・麦克布莱
Name's McBride. Frank McBride.
我第一次和不需要 我付钱的律师交谈
- First time I ever talked to a lawyer didn't cost me money. - [Chuckles]
实际上,马洛尼先生 和我交谈还能让你赚点钱
Actually, Mr. Maloney, by talking to me you could make yourself some money.
- 是吗? - 我愿意支付合理的现金
- Yeah? - I'm prepared to pay a reasonable sum of cash,
立刻付,如果你能提供给我任何 艾迪・休奎奇的资讯
right now, for any information that could lead me to Eddie Shoebridge.
我到任何地方 律师通常是带来坏消息
Where I come from, lawyers are usually bad news.
喔,不,这次不是 这次会是个好消息
Oh, no. Not this time. This time they're good news.
事实上,我认为艾迪・休奎奇 会很高兴听到我带给他的消息
Matter of fact, I think that Eddie Shoebridge...
would be delighted when he hears from me.
你要告诉他什么?
What are you gonna tell him?
嗯,我的客户要求我保密
Well, my client has asked me to keep that confidential.
谁聘请你去找这家伙?
Who hired you to find this guy?
- 这也得保密 - 我当然希望能帮你,先生…
- That's confidential also. - Sure like to help you, Mister...
这里的生意并不太好
Business ain't all that good around here.
- 我想你能帮我 - 是吗?
- I think you can help me. - Is that right?
嗯,这里的人们告诉我 艾迪・休奎奇已经死了
Mm-hmm. See, people around here have been telling me that Eddie Shoebridge is dead.
如果他死了,看来他就听不到 你要告诉他的好消息了,嗯?
[Sighs] Well, if he's dead, looks like he ain't gonna be hearir...
all that good news you have to tell him, huh?
我认为他还活着
I think he's alive.
[Sighs]
看来这辆车不需要太干净了
Sure don't keep this car very clean.
你能告诉我,为什么要在空坟上 安置墓碑吗? 马洛尼
You want to tell me why you put a headstone on an empty grave, Maloney?
什么墓碑?
What headstone?
一个你付了395美元买的 就在1965年
The one you paid $395 for back in 1965.
你欠我2.47美元,先生
You owe me $2.47, mister.
两个星期前,你到县政府申请 艾迪・休奎奇的死亡证明
Two weeks before that, you went to the county courthouse...
and asked for a certificate of death for Edward Shoebridge,
而且你被拒绝了
and you were turned down.
- 你要用信用卡支付吗? - 不
-You wanna give me your credit card? - No.
信用卡被停用了
Credit cards are out.
跟你一样,我喜欢付…现金
Like you, I prefer to pay... in cash.
这个是我个人最喜欢的
Now, this one happens to be my personal favorite.
是不是很高雅?
Isn't it exquisite?
对我来说太贵了
[Woman] Probably too expensive for me.
我能帮你吗? 先生
[Bell Dings] [Woman #2] Can I help you, sir?
抱歉,我马上回来
Excuse me. I'll be right back. Uh, Mrs. Clay?
克莱儿女士,你能帮我 接待一下坎妮安女士吗?
Would you take care of Mrs. Cunningham for a few moments?
好的,亚当森先生
Certainly, Mr. Adamson.
我担心我太过喜欢了
[Mrs. Cunningham] I'm afraid I rather like it.
嘿,艾迪,你这狗娘养的
[Joe] Hey, Eddie. You old son of a bitch.
如果对你来说都一样 我比较喜欢叫亚瑟・亚当森
If it's all the same to you, I prefer Arthur Adamson.
你来这里干嘛?
Now what in the hell are you doing here?
有要紧的事找你 就这样,艾迪…亚瑟
Had to see you about something kind of urgent. That's all, Eddie... Arthur.
- 你就不能打电话给我吗? - 有些事不能在电话里谈
- Couldrt you have phoned me? - Some things you don't put on no telephone.
嘿,你有酒吗?
Hey, uh, you got any booze around?
好吧,乔森,这次是什么事?
All right, Joseph. What is it this time?
要买新的冰箱给你老婆?
[Pouring Drink] New freezer for your wife?
老妈要做另一个手术? 赌徒威胁要杀你? 还是什么?
Mother needs another operation? Bookies threatened to kill you? What?
嘿,艾迪,你把我说得好像寄生虫
Aw, come on, Eddie. You make me sound like some kind of sponger.
我不是不感激你的帮助
Not that I ain't grateful for all your favors.
- 我有得选择吗? - 好了,好了,就这样
- Did I ever have a choice? - Okay, okay. Here it is.
首先,我得问你一个问题
[Sniffs] First off, I gotta ask you a question.
- 问吧 - 我问你,别废话,艾迪
- Go ahead. - I'm tellir ya. No shit now, Eddie.
你能想到什么理由,这么多年后 怎么会有人对你的生活感兴趣?
Can you think of any reason why anyone would be sniffir around in your life...
after all these years?
我想不出任何理由,怎么了?
I can't think of any reason at all. Why?
今天有个家伙来到车厂
Well, there's this guy comes around the garage today...
探问艾迪・休奎奇
tryir to locate Eddie Shoebridge.
他自称是个律师 有个好消息带给你
Claims he's a lawyer, he's got good news for ya.
没说是什么事,为谁工作
Wort say what, or who he's workir for.
只说他叫麦克布莱 我第一眼看到他就知道是说谎
Calls himself McBride. I know he's a phony the minute I see him.
- 警察? - 不,是业余的
- Police? - No way. He's a real amateur.
我追查他的车牌
I traced his license plates with the bureau...
也不是开他自己的车
Doesrt even drive his own car.
"布兰琪・泰勒,城堡大道17号"
"Blanche Tyler, 17 Castle Heights Road."
- 他长什么样子? - 高瘦,大约35岁
- What did he look like? - [Coughs] He's tall, thin, about 35.
他叼着一支烟斗 问许多自以为是的问题
He's always got a pipe on. Asking a lot of smart-ass questions.
- 你告诉他什么了? - 什么该死的都没说
- What'd you tell him? - Nothir. Not a goddamn thing.
我不需要说,他什么都知道
I didn't have to. He knew everything...
你叫我帮你立的假墓碑
fake headstone you had me put up,
我如何试图帮你申请死亡证明
how I tried to get you officially declared dead.
那狗娘养的还说了 他认为你还活着
The son of a bitch says he thinks you're still alive.
他在找你,艾迪
He's lookir for you, Eddie.
任何一个狗娘养的想找到你
And any son of a bitch who's lookir for you...
就会找上我
is lookir for me.
哦…
Well,
无论他有什么行动 他不会找到我的
whatever he's up to, he won't find me.
你太过担心了,乔森
You worry too much, Joseph.
是呀,我太过担心 因为你只是策划放火
Yeah, I worry too much, because you only planned the fire,
把老先生和老太太锁在卧房里
and locked your old man and old lady in the bedroom.
- 是我淋汽油,我点燃抹布 - 我很感谢你
- I poured the gasoline. I lit the rags. - And I thank you.
那是我不光彩的童年当中 最快乐的一天
The happiest day of my whole, inglorious childhood.
好吧,你想继续当孩子 我有我的做法
All right, you want to kid about it, it's all right with me.
- 我要跟踪这家伙 - 然后呢?
- I'm gonna track this guy down. - And then what?
这个…
This.
- 你永远不会改变,是吗? - 你有没有理由抱怨
- You'll never change, will you? - You got no cause to complain.
- 当你需要我,我总是在那里 - 听着,把那东西拿开
- When you needed me, I was always there, wasrt I? - Look, put that thing away.
听我说,我要你回巴洛溪
And listen to me. I want you to go back to Barlow Creek.
什么都别做,什么都别说
Do nothing, say nothing.
让我自己来解决这件事 用平静的方式
Let me look into this matter in my own, quiet way.
如果我需要你,我会和你联络
And if I need you for anything, I'll contact you.
好吗?
Okay?
你是老板,亚瑟
You're the boss, Arthur.
这很感人不是吗… 一个完美的谋杀…
Isn't it touching how... a perfect murder...
使我们的友谊 这些年来一直维系着?
has kept our friendship alive all these years?
你最好相信
You better believe it. [Knocking At Door]
抱歉,打扰了,亚当森先生
- [Door Opens] - I'm sorry to disturb you, Mr. Adamson.
有两位先生找您,从警局来的
There are two gentlemen here to see you, from the police department.
告诉他们,我马上来
Tell them I'll be right out.
老天,艾迪
[Door Closes] Jesus Christ, Eddie!
在这儿等着
[Softly] Wait here.
- 我是亚瑟・亚当森,能为您效劳? - 抱歉,打扰您
Arthur Adamson. What can I do for you gentlemen? Sorry to bother you.
我是安迪・布希检察官 这位是彼得森副官
Andy Bush, Bureau of Inspectors, and this is Lieutenant Peterson.
- 嗨 - 我的荣幸
Hi. My pleasure.
毫无疑问,你一定读过或听说过 康斯坦丁绑架案
No doubt you've been reading, or hearing, about the Constantine kidnapping.
哦,我必须承认,检察官
Well, I have a confession to make, Inspector.
当我听到那宝石的大小 我都流口水了
When I heard of the size of that stone, my mouth watered.
专业来说
Professionally speaking, of course. [Chuckles]
希望你不要感到受歧视 亚当森先生
Well, just so you don't feel discriminated against, Mr. Adamson,
我们只是对城里的每个珠宝商 和银楼做例行性询问
we're routinely covering every gem dealer and jewelry store in the city.
哦,我受宠若惊
Well, I'm flattered.
你有许多机会去接触 有注意到什么不寻常吗?
Have you, by any chance, noticed anything out of the ordinary, Mr. Adamson?
有任何异常的大小宝石 在过去几天流入市面?
Any unusual movement of large... or small... stones into the markets these last few days?
- 绝对没有 - 我明白了
- Absolutely not. - I see.
我认为你们可以假设这个,嗯… "赃物"已经被切割成较小的宝石
I take it that you're going on the assumption...
that this, uh, "ransom stone" has been cut up into smaller gems?
- 有道理,先生 - 这样更有销路
- That's correct, sir. - It makes a lot of sense.
我们也是这么认为
We think so.
如果可以 恕我冒昧地提出一项建议
If I may presume to make a suggestion,
在我看来,你们应该涵盖 古董商和二手珠宝市场
it seems to me you ought to be covering the antique and secondhand jewelry markets.
他们从任何人那里购买 而我们只向专业珠宝批发商买货
They buy from anyone, whereas we jewelers buy exclusively on the wholesale exchanges.
- 我们已经这么做了,亚当森先生 - 喔
- That's already being done, Mr. Adamson. - Oh!
我认为我们已经占用 亚当森先生太多时间了
I think we've taken up enough of Mr. Adamsors time.
很抱歉,我没能给你们 太多的帮助
Well, I'm sorry I haven't been able to be of more help to you.
不过,如果我有听到任何 不寻常的市场交易
However, if I do hear of any unusual transactions in the marketplace,
我一定会与您联系
I'll be sure and contact you.
- 好的,不胜感激,再见 - 保重
- Yes, we'd appreciate that. Much obliged. - Take care.
- 再见,先生 - 祝你们好运
- Good-bye, sir. - Good day. And good luck!
克莱儿女士,你可以关门了 我还有一些工作要做
Mrs. Clay, close up as soon as you wish. I have some work to do in here.
我会从后门离开
I'll let myself out the back way.
- 晚安 - 晚安
Good night. Good night.
(布兰琪・泰勒,城堡大道17号)
(城堡大道)
- 你的朋友布兰琪・泰勒是个灵媒 - 灵媒?
- Your friend, Blanche Tyler, is a spiritualist. - A spiritualist?
招牌上是这么写的 但没有人在家
That's what it says on her shingle. Also, there's no one home.
灵魂是永远不会在家的,上车
A spirit is never at home. Get in.
你认为我们该怎么办?
[Sighs] What do you think we should do?
我们等待 我们仍然不知道那男的是谁
We'll wait. We still don't know who the man is yet.
- 非抽不可? - 嗯哼
Must you? Mm-hmm.
那一定是她
That must be her.
那个叼着烟斗的 肯定就是去找马洛尼的人
That must be the fellow with the pipe who called on Maloney.
一个计程车司机
A cab driver.
鲁尼,鲁尼,怎么回事? 你要去哪儿?
Lumley. Lumley, what's this? Where are ya goir?
我要回家躺在自己的床上 可以好好睡个觉
I'm going home to my own bed where I can get some sleep.
不,你不会的
No, you're not.
布兰琪,你不能每件事 都要顺着你的意
Blanche, is that all you've ever got on your mind?
你留着要干嘛,未雨绸缪?
What are you saving it for, a rainy day?
亲爱的,你永远不会知道 什么时候会需要它
Honey, you never know when you're gonna need it.
你很不体贴,鲁尼
You're not being friendly, Lumley.
布兰琪,我已经精疲力尽了 我对你是没利用价值的
Blanche, I'm too pooped to pop. I'd be useless to you.
你对我总是毫无用处
You're always useless to me! [Dog Barking]
当我需要你时,你总是精疲力尽!
You're always pooping out when I need you! [Car Horn Honking]
我们可以赚一大笔钱 你说这是毫无用处?
[George] ... we can collect a huge sum of money, : You call that useless?
你知道我在说什么 来,进屋吧,别吵了
You know what I'm talking about. Come on in side and stop being difficult.
今晚不行,我不会留在这儿
Not tonight, Josephine. I'm outta here.
你这个懒虫!
- You're a fink! - If I'm a fink, you're an ungrateful bitch.
如果我是懒虫 你就是一个忘恩负义的婊子
- 那明天呢? - 怎样?
What about tomorrow? What about it?
你有重要的工作要做 我要你确认谁是艾迪・休奎…
You've got important work to do. I want you to be sure about Eddie Shoe...
跟他说!
- [Passing Car Obscures Dialog] - Talk to him!
你要告诉我多少次?
How many times are you going to tell me that?
我又要告诉你多少次 我明天的工作是开计程车?
How many times am I gonna have to tell you that tomorrow I have to work in my cab?
所以要等到礼拜天
So it'll wait till Sunday.
你最好给我一个简要 我一头雾水
You better give me a quick synopsis. I'm confused.
很简单,一个疲惫的计程车司机
Simple. A cab driver is shacked up...
和一个性饥渴的灵媒 布兰琪・泰勒
with a sex-starved medium named Blanche Tyler.
别问我为什么,但很显然 他们找到了艾迪・休奎奇的幽灵
Don't ask me why, but apparently they're on the trail...
of some spook named Eddie Shoebridge.
幸运的是,不是在追踪 你最喜欢的"赃物"和我
Fortunately, not on the trail of your favorite kidnapper and mine.
你怎么能那么肯定?
How can you be so sure?
你也听到了 他们谈论到将赚一大笔钱
You did hear him talk about collecting a huge hunk of money.
那报酬不是在我们头上?
Couldrt that be the reward that's on our heads?
你说到重点了,法兰西大姊
You got yourself a point there, Frances, old girl.
只有时间才能告诉我们 是好是坏
Only time will tell whether it's any good.
但有一件事是肯定的
One thing's certain.
我们不会改变我们的计划 不会是现在
We're not going to change our game plan. Not now.
买瓶酒给我,亚瑟
Buy me a drink, Arthur.
一辆闪亮的车
A shiny car.
一辆豪华轿车?
A... limousine?
他为什么要开得这么快,亨利?
Why does he drive so fast, Henry?
那是什么? 在他旁边座位上的?
What's that? On the seat beside him?
我听到婴儿的哭声 快,亨利,在他消失前
I hear the sound of a baby crying. Quick, Henry, before he disappears.
问他…是的,我明白
Ask... Yes, I know.
我…看到他了
I... see him now.
穿着制服,一个司机
The uniform. A chauffeur.
什么? 亨利,我要听他说话
What? Henry, I need words.
谁? 什么?
Who? The what?
兰伯特家的司机?
[Panting] The Rainbird chauffeur?
天哪,老麦克・欧基夫 我们的司机
Good heavens. Old Michael O'Keefe, our chauffeur.
麦克要去哪里?
[Gasps] Where is Michael going?
亨利,问他把哈丽叶的婴儿 带去哪里?
Henry, ask him where he's taking Harriet's baby.
噢,有太多影像,闪得太快了
Oh, more pictures are coming in too fast.
我看不清楚
I can hardly make them out.
亨利,墓地,一个墓碑?
Henry, a graveyard, a headstone?
我不喜欢这样,亨利
I don't like this, Henry.
鞋子…桥…
A shoe. Bridge.
鞋子桥? (音似休奎奇) 噢,不要这样对我,亨利
A shoe bridge? Oh, don't do this to me, Henry.
- 对司机说话 - 噢,上帝,有东西在燃烧
- Speak to the chauffeur. - Oh, God, something's burning.
是房子,快,亨利,房子着火了
The house. Quick, Henry. The house is on fire.
带我离开这里
Take me away from here.
我不想看这些
I don't want to see this.
我受不了他们可怕的尖叫声
I can't bear the sound of their awful screaming.
回到司机那里,亨利 让麦克加入我们
Go back to the chauffeur, Henry. Get Michael into our presence.
兰伯特女士记得他
Miss Rainbird remembers him.
是的,我记得
Yes, I remember.
布兰琪夫人,让我来说
Madame Blanche, listen to me.
你能听到我吗?
Can you hear me?
我想起一件事,这非常重要
I've remembered something else that could be terribly important.
等一下,亨利,在你走之前
Wait one minute, Henry. Before you go,
兰伯特女士需要知道 哈丽叶孩子的情况
Miss Rainbird deserves some kind of assurance about Harriet's child.
他现在是个大人了
He's a man by now,
我们想知道他现在快乐吗?
and we have to know, is he happy, Henry?
他还活着吗? 过得幸福吗?
Is he alive and well and happy?
如果你不能…
If you can't, you can't.
我当然不能强迫你
I certainly can't force you.
是,当然,她会理解的
Yes. Of course she'll understand.
直到下一次,那么,再见了
Until next time, then. Good-bye.
再见,亲爱的
Good-bye, my love.
- 发生什么事? - 难道你不记得了?
- What happened? - Don't you remember?
- 并不太愉快 - 噢,没关系了
- Not a blessed thing. - Oh, it doesn't matter now.
听着,听着,布兰琪夫人
Listen, listen, Madame Blanche.
你的亨利拾回了 我完全遗忘的记忆
Your Henry jogged my memory of something I'd completely forgotten.
当我们可怜的老司机麦克 意识到他即将死亡时
When our poor old chauffeur, Mike, realized he was dying,
他写信给我,说世上有个人…
he wrote to me and said there was one person on earth...
他许下承诺说
who had promised that he'd make it his business...
只要他还活着 就能够知道哈丽叶的儿子在哪儿
to know where Harriet's son was as long as he lived.
是个牧师,帮新生婴儿洗礼的
It was the parson who baptized the newborn baby.
还有一件事我要告诉你…
And there's an additional thing I can tell you.
别告诉我,让我猜猜看
Don't tell me. Let me guess.
- 500美元 - 没钱,连100也没有
- Five hundred. - Not a penny. Not even a hundred for expenses.
这是全有或全无,乔治
It's all or nothing, George,
直到我可以找出 他的名字和现在的住址
until I can produce his name and his present address.
- 老天,布兰琪 - 不过,她给了我一条重大线索
- Jesus, Blanche. - However, she gave me a marvelous clue.
- 我们又来了 - 不,是你有得忙了…
- Here we go again. - No, here you go again...
有一个人可以告诉你 休奎奇是生是死
to the man who might tell you if Shoebridge is dead or alive.
- 那是谁? - 圣安塞尔姆大教堂的伍德主教
- Who's that? - Bishop Wood at St. Anselm's Cathedral.
- 老天爷,布兰琪 - 不,乔治,不是k
- Holy Christ, Blanche. - No, George, not him.
是圣安塞尔姆大教堂的伍德主教
Bishop Wood at St. Anselm's Cathedral.
他曾经是一个牧师 替婴儿时期的休奎奇受洗过
He was a parson once and he baptized the Shoebridge baby.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
抱歉
Sorry.
你知道我要怎样 才能约见伍德主教?
Do you know how I could, uh, make a date to see Bishop Wood?
如果你想今天约见 你必须先找牧师
If you want to make the appointment today, you'll have to make it through the chaplain.
哪一个是牧师?
Which one is the chaplain?
礼拜结束后,我会带你去的
When the service is over, I'll show you where to go.
噢,亲爱的
Oh, dear.
[Congregation Chattering]
你知道他还在动 你确定给他的用量足够?
You know he's moving. You sure you gave him enough?
只是一般的剂量 他看起来无害
Just the usual dose. He looks so harmless.
当我还是个孩子时 住在这个村庄
When I was a little kid living in that village,
他总是让我觉得 我是个邪恶的东西
he always made me feel like I was something evil.
- 看看我现在 - 我觉得年轻了几岁
- And look at me now. - I feel years younger.
你知道,多一个像这样的今天 我们将一脸土灰
You know, one more like this one today, and we'll be naturally gray.
这是一个令人难以置信的工作 我真的认为这超过100万
It was an incredible job. I really think it's won'th more than a million.
抱歉,亲爱的,但我可不想回去 重写我的赎金纸条
I'm sorry, darling, but I'm not going back...
那将背离了我的祈祷书
and rewrite my ransom note that I left in my prayer book.
你必须好好动一动 去解决这100万
You'll have to be a good sport and settle for a million.
你很漂亮,法兰,很漂亮
You were beautiful, Fran. Just beautiful.
- 我很害怕 - 我告诉过你没问题的,不是吗?
- I was scared. - I told you it'd be all right, didn't I?
人们在教堂是很守礼节的
People in church are inibited.
他们不会跳起来乱跑 或是制造噪音,他们都虔诚有礼
They don't jump up and run around and make a lot of noise.
They're all too religiously polite.
我们要继续自我陶醉 或是你想谈谈他呢?
Shall we go on congratulating ourselves,
or would you like to talk about him now?
- 谁? - 谁?
- Who? - "Who."
那个叼着烟斗的男人
The man with the pipe.
- 你看到他在那里? - 如影随形
- So you saw him there, huh? - Larger than life.
比死亡还难缠
Larger than death, you mean.
他现在追求的毫无疑问了
There's no doubt about who he's after now.
你打算怎么处理他,亲爱的
What were you planning to do about him, dear,
除了不想告诉我的以外?
besides just not telling me?
我不打算对他做任何事情
I'm not planning to do anything about him.
乔森・马洛尼渴望的那份工作 现在他得到了
Joe Maloney's been itching for that job. He's got it.
我会打电话给他 等我把我们的客人安置好后
I'll phone him as soon as we put our guest in his quarters.
我说得对,那计程车司机真傻
I was right about that silly cab driver.
在我的生命里 这次我讨厌说对了
For once in my life I hate being right.
他怎么会知道我们要去那里 除了你和我,世上还有谁会知道?
Well, how in the hell could he have known we were going to be there...
when you and I are the only two people in the world who knew that?
我有一个想法
[Sighs] I've got a thought.
- 就是有点愚蠢 - 说吧
- It's a dumb one. - Say it.
你相信特异功能吗?
Do you believe in E.S.P.?
特异功能,超常的心灵现象
Extra sensory perception, all that psychic phenomena?
什么意思? 是说那个叫什么的夫人?
What do you mean? Madame What's-her-name?
布兰琪・泰勒
Blanche Tyler.
老天
Jesus.
你和我都知道这一面墙 但我们能犯错吗?
You and I know that that's off the wall, but, uh, can we afford to be wrong?
恐怕我们的那对欢喜冤家 将会共同发生一起致命的事故
I'm afraid our two quarrelsome lovers are going to have to share a fatal accident.
噢,我的天啊
Oh, my God.
但马洛尼不会这么做的,对吧?
But Maloney wouldn't be willing to do that, would he?
当然,他会很乐意做的
Of course he'd be willing. Gladly.
他会相信那是为了保护自己 和他的老伙伴
He'd believe he was protecting himself and his old buddy.
我不想知道,好吗?
I don't want to know about it. Okay?
- 答应我,亚瑟 - 拜托,亲爱的
- Promise me, Arthur. - Come on, now, dear.
这有什么好激动的
That's what's so exciting about all of this.
我们同生共死 没有什么好退缩的
We move as one. Everything together. Nothing held back.
这是严重的疏失,就这样失去他 他是我们的所有
It was gross negligence, losing him that way. He was all we had.
我没有失去他,他只是被绑架
I didn't lose him. He was kidnapped.
为什么会有人对主教干这种事?
Why would anyone want to do that to a bishop?
为了赎金啊,傻瓜 那可是100万美元
For the ransom, dummy. It's a million dollars.
我无能为力,你知道,我就在那儿
I can't get over it. You know, I was right there.
噢,忘了那100万吧 我们的一万该怎么办?
Tsk. Oh, forget about the million. What about out 10,000?
我们现在无路可走,鲁尼
We've got nowhere to go now, Lumley.
我该怎么告诉兰伯特女士?
What am I gonna tell Miss Rainbird?
看来我和亨利又得费尽心力 来补原本该是你的工作
I suppose Henry and I are going to have to exhaust ourselves again doing your work for you.
什么意思,我的工作? 我的工作是驾驶该死的计程车
What d'ya mean, my work? My work is driving a goddamn cab,
for Christ's sake.
看在上帝的分上 从这一分钟开始,做点正确的…
And startir right this minute, that's exact... [Phone Ringing]
- 正确的什么? 继续说 - 接电话
- That's exact what? Go ahead. - Answer the telephone.
哈罗? 谁?
Hello? Who?
马洛尼先生?
Mr. Maloney?
巴洛溪? 请继续
Barlow Creek? Go ahead.
哈罗
Hello.
你能说大声一点吗? 马洛尼先生
Can you speak a little louder, Mr. Maloney?
我说我透过你那律师朋友 驾驶的车牌号码追查到你
I said I traced you through the license plates on that car your lawyer friend was driving.
我猜你仍然想寻找艾迪・休奎奇
I figured if you was still lookir for some dope on Eddie Shoebridge,
- 我可以给你一点情报 - 哦
- I might have somethir for you. - Oh.
你为什么改变主意了 马洛尼先生?
How come you changed your mind, Mr. Maloney?
我没和你的人说 是因为我觉得不关我的事
I didn't say nothir to your man 'cause I felt it was none of my business and none of his,
但我一直在想 我可以因此赚点外快
but I been thinkir about it and how I could use the bread.
因此考虑过后 我愿意带你去见一个人
So for a little consideration, I'm willing to lead you to someone...
他认识艾迪・休奎奇的太太
who knows Eddie Shoebridge's wife.
你得付一大笔钱
It'll cost you a grand. [Laughs]
喔,别傻了,马洛尼先生
Oh, don't be silly, Mr. Maloney.
我的律师就在我的身边
I have my lawyer right here beside me,
他说愿意付你100美元 只要能找到人
and he says he'll give you $100 provided it leads to something.
Make it two.
喔,好吧,成交
Oh... All right. It's a deal.
- 我们在哪碰面? - 你和你的律师朋友…
- Where do we meet? - You and that lawyer friend of yours,
你们开车来 两个小时后在梅布斯见面
you drive up and meet me at Abe and Mabel's in two hours.
- 梅布斯? - 是路边咖啡屋,在榭尔曼路上
- Abe and Mabel's? - It's a cafe up the road to Mt. Sherman,
进入22号公路后大约五英哩 你知道哪里吗?
about five miles off Route 22.
- You know where it is? - Yeah. Why so far away?
知道,为什么到那么远? 我们不能找个更方便的地方吗?
Can't we meet somewhere more convenient?
我要带你去的派对就在那边
This party I'm gonna take you to happens to be up in that area.
我明白了,马洛尼先生 你肯定艾迪・休奎奇还活着?
I see. Mr. Maloney, are you admitting Edward Shoebridge is still alive?
两个小时后 我看到白花花的钞票再说
I ain't sayir a thing till I see the color of your money, in two hours.
- 你怎么想? - 我闻到鱼腥味
- What d'ya think? - Smells fishy to me.
我知道
I know.
但是当你快饿死时 甚至鱼腥味都会觉得好
But even fish smells good when you're starving to death.
我们会有什么损失? 他是唯一的线索
What have we got to lose? He's the only clue left.
你有200美元吗?
You got $200 on you?
你比我更清楚
You know me better than that.
当然没有,再给我一个
Of course not. Fix me another one of these.
你不需要,你已经有一个了 我们只有两个小时去那里
You don't need another one. You already got one. We only got two hours to get there.
- 我要在车上吃 - 走吧
- I'll eat it in the car. - Come on.
你真难应付
You're impossible.
两杯啤酒,麻烦
A couple of beers, please.
他迟到了
He must be late.
谢谢
Thank you, dear. [Car Approaching, Brakes Squeal]
孩子们,去坐那边
You kids sit over there.
- 哦,今天周日的学校如何? - 吵死了
How was Sunday school today? Noisy.
- 五瓶可乐,麻烦 - 我们没有吵啊
- Five Cokes, please. - We didn't make any noise.
这就对了,所以你才在这里
That's right. That's why you're here.
不要怪我
Don't blame me.
我有说什么吗?
Did I say anything? [Door Opens, Closes]
- 你好,抱歉,我迟到了 - 我帮你搬张椅子
- Hello. I'm sorry I'm late. - I'll get you a chair.
- 没关系,我坐这儿 - 我和你坐一起
That's all right. I'll sit over here. I'll join you.
瞧,好手段
Look at that. Nice arrangement.
别下流了,乔治
Don't be obscene, George.
喔
Oh.
谢谢,亲爱的
Thank you, my dear.
让头脑保持清醒,好吗?
Just see that you keep you head screwed on straight, will you?
他不会来了
He's not coming.
噢,就这样结束了
Well, that's the end of that.
乔治,在急什么?
George, what's the big hurry?
开慢一点,好吗?
Just slow down a little, will ya, please?
我说了别开那么快,乔治!
I told you not to drive so fast, George!
我不知道怎么回事 油门好像卡住了
I don't know what's wrong. The accelerator seems to be sticking.
乔治,看在老天的份上 开慢点,好吗?
George, for God's sake, slow up, will ya?
我做不到
[Tires Screeching] I can't.
我的汉堡快要吐出来了
My hamburger's coming up.
油门…卡住了
The accelerator... is stuck.
踩煞车!
Use the brakes!
- 没反应 - 什么?
- They don't work. - What?
- 煞车没反应 - 什么意思?
- The brakes don't work. - What do you mean?
- 乔治 - 拜托,别抓我,看在老天的份上!
- George! - Come on, woman. Don't grab me, for God's sake!
不是我,是煞车坏了
It's not me. It's the brakes don't work.
我快得心脏病了,乔治
I'm getting violently ill, George.
- 你快让我窒息了,布兰琪,老天 - 乔治
- You're chokir me, Blanche, for Christ's sake! - George!
快想办法!
Do something!
拉手煞车! 伸手拉手煞车!
Grab the brake! Reach down and pull the hand brake.
- 快拉 - 我在拉了!
- Pull on it! - I am pulling!
你的手别抓方向盘,快拉!
Get your hands off the steering wheel. Pull on it!
- 我在拉了 - 快拉
- I am pulling. - Pull it.
快啊
Come on.
你的手别抓方向盘,该死的!
Get your hand off the goddamn wheel!
我得离开这条路
- [Horns Honking] - I gotta get off this road.
布兰琪,坚持住
Blanche, just hang on.
有趣吗?
Wasrt that fun?
- 去你的,乔治・鲁尼 - 你吃错药啦?
- Damn you, George Lumley! - What's the matter with you?
- 不是我,是马洛尼 - 开车的不是他!
It wasrt me. It's Maloney. He wasrt driving!
那当然,是他对车动了手脚 弄坏了煞车
Of course, but he screwed up the car and broke the brakes.
- 马洛尼? - 没错
- Maloney? - Yes.
你认为这是巧合,布兰琪?
You think it's a coincidence, Blanche?
嗯?
Huh?
你的车…可能要大修几天了
Your car... is gonna be out of commission for a couple days.
我们想个办法回家吧
So let's go find us another way to get home.
乔治,你没事吧?
George. Are you all right?
嗯,我想是吧,你呢?
Mm-hmm. I think so. How about you?
我很好,对不起
I'm okay. I'm sorry.
- 你真的认为马洛尼要我们死? - 嗯哼
- Do you really think Maloney wanted us dead? - Mm-hmm.
为什么? 老天 为何有人会想这样对我们?
Why, in the name of God, would anyone want to do that to us?
我不知道
I don't know,
但可以打赌,肯定和你那个 神秘的朋友艾迪・休奎奇有关
but you can bet is has something to do with your mysterious friend, Eddie Shoebridge.
或许马洛尼就把他埋在他家后院
Maloney's probably got him buried in his backyard.
不希望被我们给找到
Doesrt want us to find out.
那边
That way.
你好,抱歉,迟到了
Hi there. Sorry I'm late.
恭喜你对我们的车干的好事 做得很完美,马洛尼
Congratulations on the nice job you did on our car, Maloney.
为什么你们俩要站在路中间?
What are you two doir standir in the middle of the road?
你明知我们为何站在路上 马洛尼
You know perfectly well what we're doing on the road, Maloney.
你一定就是布兰琪・泰勒 很高兴见到你,你的车子呢?
You must be Blanche Tyler. Pleased to meet ya. Where's your car?
这么说吧,它不太听话 你明白我的意思吧?
Let's just say it ain't in runnir order, you know what I mean?
上车,我载你们到最近的车站
Hop in. I'll give ya a lift to the nearest station.
不,谢了,我们不坐灵车
No, thank you. We don't ride in hearses.
你以为我是来这里玩的?
You think I came up here for the fun of it?
是你要我带你去派对 那人认识艾迪・休奎奇的太太啊
Then you want me to take you to this party that knows Eddie Shoebridge's wife.
你为什么不继续前进,自己走吧 马洛尼,我们当没看到
Why don't you just go ahead, uh, by yourself this time, Maloney. We'll skip it.
他真是迷人
He's all charm.
那是谁?
[Blanche] Who's that?
是马洛尼,他跟着我们
That's Maloney. He's after us.
快点
Come on.
嘿,伙计们,我们快闪
[Man] Hey, guys, let's get the hell outta here.
我们最好通知警察
We better get the police.
然后损失我们的一万美元?
And lose our $10,000?
我能帮你吗? 夫人
May I be of some help to you, madam?
- 我想看一些手镯 - 要特定款式吗?
- I'd like to see some bracelets. - Any particular kind?
你有绿宝石或珍珠的吗?
Do you have anything with turquoise, or perhaps pearls?
- 我们的客人还好吗? - 他很好
- Anything wrong with our houseguest? - He's fine.
我给了他一顿丰盛的午餐 和一瓶新产的红酒
I gave him a very nice lunch and a fresh bottle of wine.
- 或许这其中一条会吸引你? - 这些是海洋珍珠?
- Maybe one of these will appeal to you? - Are those seed pearls?
是的
That's right.
- 你来这里干嘛? - 这些看起来像淡水珍珠
- What are you doing here? - These look like freshwater pearls.
有消息传来
The message has come through on KFAG.
他们已经准备好 我们所提出的宝石了
They've located the stone we asked for.
在纽约温士顿
In New York. Harry Winston.
53克拉
Fifty-three carats.
这些都很好,多少钱?
These are very nice. How much are they?
315美元,含税
$315, including tax.
我们什么时候行动?
When do we make the pickup?
明晚9:30
Tomorrow night, 9:30.
好的,现在回家吧
Good. Now go on home.
你能不能把这些先预留下来
Would it be possible for you to set these aside...
以便我可以带丈夫过来看看?
so that I can bring in my husband and he can look at them?
当然可以,夫人
Of course, madam.
还有一个坏消息
[Sighs] Now for the bad news.
看看这个
Take a look at this.
(男子死于公路离奇事故)
没用的废物,他搞砸了
Incompetent bastard. He blew it.
现在我们得自己去干掉他们
Now we'll have to eliminate these two ourselves.
- 我们? - 没错
- Ourselves? - That's right.
明晚,等我们把客人送走后
Tomorrow night, right after we return our guest.
- 我不行 - 你必须做
- I can't. - You must.
记着,共谋等同于主谋
Remember: Share and share alike.
你别说了! 别说了!
You stop it! Stop it!
- 决定了吗? - 这个好
- Decide on something? - That'll be fine.
我要这一个
I'll have it wrapped.
但不仅如此,远远不止于此
[Man] But it was more than that, much more than that...
你留下了生命中珍贵的礼物
that you left behind as your precious gift to life.
是的,乔森・马洛尼 你是一个慷慨的人
Yes, Joseph Maloney, you were a generous man.
你献出了你的心和灵魂
You gave of your heart and soul.
你献出了最好的你
You gave the very best that was in you,
凡世上无人比你付出的更多
and no more than that can be asked of mortal man on this earth.
你深爱你的妻子
You loved your wife dearly.
你给予你亲爱的母亲和父亲
You bestowed upon your dear mother and father...
所有的照料,所有的关心
all the care, all the attention,
在他们的晚年 给予他们需要的耐心和安慰
patience and comfort that they needed...
in the sunset of their lives.
我们这些留下的人们
And those of us who are left behind...
为你而哀伤,乔森
to grieve for you, Joseph,
只能遵从上帝的决定
can only bow to the divine judgement of our Lord,
谁选择了带你远离我们
who has chosen to take you away from us...
在一场残酷的意外
in this cruel accident.
喔,神圣伟大的主啊
Oh, how great the holiness of our God.
k拥有一切智慧
For He knoweth all things.
k无所不知
And there is not anything save He knows it.
k来到了这个世界
And He cometh into the world...
k可以拯救世人 如果他们能去倾听k的声音
that He may save all men if they will harken unto His voice.
因为k看到了世人遭受的痛苦
For behold, He suffered that the pains of all men.
是的,每一个活着的生命 都在遭受痛苦
Yea, the pains of every living creature,
男人、女人和孩童…
both men, women and children...
你就不能让我独自一人吗?
Can't you leave me alone?
你杀了他还不够吗?
Isn't it enough that you killed him?
并非如此,马洛尼太太 事情正好相反
That's not so, Mrs. Maloney. It was the other way.
是你,是你来这里之后 开始了一切
You. You started it all coming here...
并且在你那交易中 把事情搞得一团糟
and messing in things that were none of your business.
请走开,拜托
Now go away. Please!
- 马洛尼太太,我要和你谈谈 - 他已经死了,埋葬了
- Mrs. Maloney, I have to talk to you. - He's dead and buried.
- 没有什么可谈的 - 他为什么不想要我…
- There's nothing to talk about. - Why didn't he want me...
- 寻找艾迪・休奎奇? - 我不想听你说话
- Iooking for Eddie Shoebridge? - I am not listening to you.
- 离开我! - 马洛尼太太,你丈夫要杀我
- Get away from me! - Mrs. Maloney, your husband tried to kill me,
- 你也有份,是吗? - 不
- and you were in on it, werert you? - No.
- 那为何总是逃避我? 那就是原因? - 不
- Then why are you always running away from me? Is that why? - No.
你知道你是企图谋杀的共犯吗?
Do you realize that you are an accessory to an attempted murder?
- 与我无关 - 也许警方会认为你也有份
- I had nothing to do with that. - Perhaps the police would think that you did.
- 你要我去跟警察说吗? - 看在老天的份上
- You want me to go to the police about it? - For God's sake.
- 你不会那样… - 告诉我艾迪・休奎奇在哪儿?
- You wouldn't do that... - Just tell me where is Eddie Shoebridge?
- 我不能 - 马洛尼太太,他在哪? 请告诉我
I can't. Mrs. Maloney, where is he? Please tell me.
没有艾迪・休奎奇
There is no Eddie Shoebridge.
他如烟雾般25年前来到这都市
He went up in smoke 25 years ago and came down in the city.
他自称亚瑟・亚当森
He calls himself Arthur Adamson.
亚瑟・亚当森?
Arthur Adamson?
如果他发现我告诉了你 他会杀了我
If he finds out I told you, he'll kill me.
走开吧,别再靠近我了
Now go away, and don't ever come near me again.
骗子! 骗子!
Fake! Fake! [Sobbing]
(艾迪・休奎奇)
等等,你这是在夸大
Wait a second, now. You're the one that's exaggerating.
不,不,我是失踪了两三天 但不可能更多了
No, I'll give you two or three days maybe I missed, but never more than that.
- 告诉他这非常重要 - 嘘
- Tell him it's deeply important. - Shh!
- 硬起来 - 为何是我?
- Stand up. - Why me?
是什么使你认为是我跑超过里程?
What makes you think that it's me that ran up all the extra mileage?
那些家伙如何,贺比或艾尔 值日班的人
What about that little asshole, Herbie, or, uh, Al, the one on the day shift?
我明白了,我会去的
I understand. I'll be there.
是,我保证我会过去
Yes, I promise I'll be there.
答案是不行
The answer's no.
他说我必须轮班 并且我今晚就要上工
He says I must work the shift, and I must work it tonight.
帮我个忙,布兰琪
And do me a favor, Blanche.
拜托别再给我制造麻烦
Please don't give me a hard time.
你没有全力去抗争
You didn't put up much of a fight.
亲爱的,听着 我一直消磨时间在帮你
Honey, look. After all the goofir off I've been doir on your behalf,
我差点就要失去我的驾驶座 被踢出公司了
I'm within a gnat's eyelash of losir my cab and gettir kicked right out of the company.
鲁尼,你真傻! 你不需要开计程车
Lumley, you're thick! You won't have to drive a cab...
如果你能把这件事办好 就能拿到钱啊
if you can get this thing over and done with and collect the money.
"如果",亲爱的 你总是对我说如果
"If," darling. You're always givir me ifs.
我不能靠如果吃饭,你也不能
I can't eat ifs and neither can you,
朱莉亚・兰伯特和你之间的 华尔滋太过遥远了
while Julia Rainbird and you are waltzir around in the great beyond.
拜托,亲爱的 我该做的就是回去工作
Come on, sweetheart. The least I can do is show up for work every now and then.
至少,我不是已经给你 那家伙的名字了吗?
After all, didn't I give you the guy's name?
但是电话簿里满满的都是 亚瑟・亚当森
But the phone book is full of Arthur Adamsons.
这很简单,你要做的 就是找出正确的那一个
It's very simple. All you need to do is find out the right one.
那很容易,一个大约40岁
That's a snap. The one that's close to 40 years old...
听到艾迪・休奎奇这名字 就会颤抖的家伙
and trembles a little bit at the name Eddie Shoebridge.
- 简单,我们明天来做 - 现在做会更好
- Easy. We do that tomorrow. - Now would be much better.
食物就要到手了,鲁尼 拜托你,亲爱的
A bird in the hand, Lumley. Please. Oh, sweetheart.
唯一的食物是在我的手上
The only bird that's gonna be in my hand...
我必须遗憾地说
and I'm very sorry to say this...
四点至午夜我必须开车
is a steering wheel from 4:00 to midnight.
好吧,我何时才能得到一个吻?
Sure. Why should I get a kiss?
当我开始认为 你不再难以忍受的时候
Just when I was beginning to think you werert impossible.
也许没有你我也能做到
Maybe I'll do it without you.
绝不可能!
The hell you will!
来吧,布兰琪,拜托
Come on, now. Please.
这个休奎奇惹了许多麻烦 不想被发现
This Shoebridge fellow's gone to a lot of trouble not to be found.
如今你不知道会被卷入 什么麻烦当中
Now you got no idea what kind of trouble you could get into.
不管是什么,他会忘了那些事的
Whatever it is, he'll forget about it...
当他听到他将获得数百万时
when he hears about the millions he's coming into.
噢,布兰琪,拜托
Oh, Blanche, come on.
坐下吧,你漂亮的小…屁股
Just sit down on your pretty little... behind.
我得说,这很…
And I must say, it is quite an...
不,这是很吸引人的小屁股
No, it is. Very attractive little behind.
等我,好吗?
Just wait for me, okay?
今晚我回到家,我们会…
And tonight when I get home, we will, uh...
很好,好好地商量我们的策略
Right. Very nice. Plot our strategy.
明白我的意思吗? 亲爱的
Know what I mean, darlir?
谁需要他
Who needs him.
(亚当森医生)
[Buzzer Buzzing]
你不会是亚瑟・亚当森,对吧?
You wouldn't be Arthur Adamson, would you?
抱歉
Excuse me.
(亚当森空调)
抱歉!
Excuse me!
哈罗,你是亚瑟・亚当森?
Hello. Are you Arthur Adamson?
嘿,亚瑟!
Hey, Art!
什么事?
Yeah?
(亚当森车厂)
(A.A.亚当森管理员)
[Doorbell Ringing]
(亚当森珠宝)
对不起,我们打烊了
I'm sorry. We're just closing.
我知道,我不是要购物 请问亚当森先生在吗?
I understand. I'm not shopping. Is Mr. Adamson around?
- 不,他不在,但你可以明天再来 - 好的
I'm afraid not. But if you come back tomorrow...
All right.
但是为了确认是我要找的 亚当森先生
But just to be sure I have the right Mr. Adamson,
- 我猜他是一位年约40岁的绅士? - 是的,没错
- he is a gentleman of about 40, I trust? - Yes, that's about right.
噢,整个下午以来 这是第一个令人鼓舞的消息
Oh, that's the first encouraging news I've had all afternoon.
为了不耽误时间 我到哪里能找到他?
Isn't there someplace I might reach him without delay?
- 你是说今晚? - 是的
- You mean tonight? - Yes.
他平常都会直接从这里回家
Well, he usually goes directly home from here.
但今晚很不幸 因为我想他今天要开个派对
But tonight would be very bad because I believe he's giving a party.
我知道他今天提早离开 是为了这个原因
I know he left unusually early for some such reason.
是不是有什么我可以帮你转达的 在明天早上?
Isn't there something I can tell him for you in the morning?
- 这是私人事情,相当私人 - 喔,我明白了
- This is personal. Rather personal. - Oh, I see.
或是你想留个字条给他
Perhaps you'd like to leave him a note.
- 字条? 是的 - 好的,请这边走
- A note? Very good. - Yes. Come this way.
抱歉
Excuse me.
谢谢
Thank you.
有什么问题吗?
Is anything the matter?
嗯,我只是在想…
Uh, I was, uh, just thinking.
与其留字条在这里
Instead of leaving this note here,
不如这样会更好,我今晚 就发个电报给亚当森先生
it might be better if I sent Mr. Adamson a telegram tonight.
- 能告诉我他的地址吗? - 呃,我不能…
- What's his address, please? - Well, I don't...
没关系的,我们是朋友
It's all right. We're friends.
- 富兰克林街1001号 - 富兰克林街1001号
- 1001 Franklin Street. - 1001 Franklin.
非常感谢你,你真是亲切
Thank you very much. You've been very kind.
你是摩羯座的吗?
You're a Capricorn, aren't you?
不,我是狮子座
No, I'm a Leo.
我想也是
That's what I thought.
- 皮特,嗨 - 哈罗,布兰琪宝贝
- Pete, hi. - Hello, there, Blanche, baby.
- 你有看到乔治吗? - 他几分钟前刚离开,很快会回来
- Have you seen George? - He just left a few minutes ago, but he'll be back.
送四个人到河谷参加派对
Took a party of four out to River Valley.
- 喔,亲爱的,那可能要通宵 - 放轻松,有什么事吗?
- Oh, dear. That could take all night. - Easily. What's up?
- 你能帮我传个话给他吗? - 当然可以
- Would you give him a message for me? - Sure thing.
- 告诉他说我找到他了 - 你找到他?
- Just tell him I found him. - You found him?
- 没错,他住在富兰克林1001号 - 富兰克林1001号
- That's right. He lives at 1001 Franklin. - 1001 Franklin.
那就是他的住所 而我现在就要过去
That's where he lives, and that's where I'm going now.
你找到他了,那就是他的住所 并且你现在就要过去
You found him, and that's where he lives, and that's where you're going now.
- 谢谢,皮特 - 随时候劳,布兰琪
- Thanks, Pete. - Any time, Blanche.
你要去踩点了?
You wanna go over the new pickup spot once again?
我记在心里
I know it by heart.
你没问题吧?
Are you all right?
- 我没问题 - 你确定?
- I will be. - You sure?
必须在9:30前到达,我们走吧
Have to be there at 9:30. Let's get going.
伍德主教,该走了
Bishop Wood, it's time to go.
你有穿上你的法衣吗?
Have you your vestments on?
是的,但我还没吃完鸡
Yes, but I haven't finished the chicken.
对不起,阁下
I'm sorry, Your Excellency.
我要你照以下说的做
Here's what I want you to do.
请把椅子放在房间中央
Place the armchair in the center of the room...
背对着门,坐在椅子上
facing away from the door and seat yourself in it.
你会睡得很安稳
You're going to be comfortably put to sleep.
只是一小段时间
But it'll last only for a short while.
非常感谢你,你想得真周到
Thank you very much. You are most considerate.
当你准备好后,让我知道
Let me know when you're ready.
顺便说一下,我还没看完那本书
By the way. I haven't quite finished that book...
你让我看书真好
you were kind enough to let me have.
我想…能让我带走吗?
May I, uh, take it along?
好带走我们的指纹?
With our fingerprints on it? Tsk, tsk, tsk.
不错的尝试,阁下
Nice try, Your Excellency.
谢谢,不烦你了,我准备好了
Thank you. Don't bother, then. I'm ready.
好的,我会把你的灯熄灭
All right, I'll be turning your light off now.
我们不能迟到,看看是谁,小心点
We mustrt be late. See who it is, and be careful.
是她,那个女人,布兰琪・泰勒
[Whispering] It's her. That woman. Blanche Tyler.
简直难以置信!
[Whispering] This is incredible!
- 计程车司机和她在一起? - 只有她
- Is that cab driver with her? - She's alone.
如果我不是要在35分钟内办事…
If I didn't have to make this pickup in 35 minutes...
我们应该怎么做?
What are we going to do?
什么也别做!
Nothing!
等一会儿
Until later tonight.
- 她不见了 - 快点,走吧
- She's gone. - Come on. Let's go.
快,快,快!
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
(亲爱的亚当森先生)
(或者该称呼您休奎奇先生)
(请您回电给我)
(我有个天大的好消息要告诉你)
- 我想你说过… - 我知道
- I thought you said... - I know.
- 亚当森先生? - 看着他
- Mr. Adamson? - Watch him.
喔,亚当森先生 真幸运,我没有错过你
Oh, Mr. Adamson. How lucky I am not to have missed you.
- 显然你没有听到我在前门按铃 - 显然是
- Apparently you didn't hear me at the front door. - Apparently.
我叫布兰琪・泰勒,是个通灵师
I am Madame Blanche Tyler, the spiritualist.
晚安,甜心
Good evening, honey.
布兰琪女士,我能麻烦你 把你的车移开我们的车道吗?
Madame Blanche, I wonder if I might suggest to you to remove your car from our driveway.
- 我们约会快迟到了 - 喔,是的
- We're terribly late for an appointment. - Well, yes.
当你听到我来的原因 亚当森先生…或者该称呼休奎奇?
When you hear why I've come, Mr. Adamson... Or should I say Shoebridge?
- 你就不会介意迟到了 - 我亲爱的女士
- You won't mind being late at all. - My dear lady,
- 我很清楚你来的原因 - 你怎么知道的?
- I know exactly why you've come here. - How could you?
- 你和你的朋友,那个计程车司机… - 你认识乔治?
- And exactly why you and your friend, that cab driver... - You know George?
过去几个星期以来一直在追查我 就好像两条嗜血的猎犬
Have been sniffing along my trail like two eager bloodhounds these past few weeks.
我没有这样想,亚当森先生
I had no idea, Mr. Adamson.
- 好吧,布兰琪女士,你找到我了 - 真是好极了
- All right, Madame Blanche, you found me. - Music to my ears.
我非常愿意听取你的要求 不论是什么,但不是现在
I'm perfectly willing to listen to your demands, whatever they might be, but not right now.
没有要求,亚当森先生 噢,不,不,不
No demands, Mr. Adamson. Oh, no, no, no!
是几乎没有,朱莉亚・兰伯特 不会向你要求什么…
Hardly that. Julia Rainbird wants nothing from you...
但是你必须做她的继承人 继承所有兰伯特家的财富
but the privilege of making you heir to the entire Rainbird fortune.
所有的,动人的数百万美元
The whole, lovely millions and millions of it.
如果她有提出任何要求 那就是要我找到你
Now if she made any demands at all, they were on me to find you.
透过通灵的手段,那是当然的
Through psychic means, of course.
让我搞清楚一下,这就是你和 你的朋友一直追查我的原因?
Let me get this straight. Is that the only reason you and your friend have been,
shall we say, investigating me?
喔,是的,不要以为这很容易
Oh, yes. And don't think it's been easy.
噢,亚当森先生 你给了我和乔治魔鬼般的考验
Oh, Mr. Adamson, you've given George and me the devil's own time of it.
追踪打从你婴儿时期被遗弃开始
Tracing you from a foundling baby...
一直到叫做休奎奇的青年 然后是叫做亚当森的男士
to a young boy named Shoebridge to a man named Adamson.
噢,但是,亚当森先生 你就在这里,我也在这里
Oh, but, Mr. Adamson, here you are, : Here I am.
这对我们来说 真是快乐的时刻,不是吗?
- It's a happy moment for us all, isn't it? - [Fran Gasps]
是主教
[Blanche] It's the Bishop. [Gasps]
有谁知道你来这里?
Does anyone know that you've come here?
没有人知道…
No one know...
有谁会知道?
Anyone kn-know?
不,连灵魂也没有
No. Not a soul.
即使是乔治的灵魂
Not even George soul.
你没有什么好担心的 亚当森先生
You have nothing to worry about, Mr. Adamson.
我保证
I promise.
我不会吐露半个字…给任何人
I won't breathe a word... to anyone.
看来布兰琪・泰勒女士 需要休息一下
It looks like Miss Tyler needs some rest.
你不听我的话?
Will you do as I say?
不,不
No. No.
打开门
Unlock the door.
高兴一点,法兰
Cheer up, Fran.
让我们去取新的钻石 来装饰我们的吊灯吧
Let's go get the new diamond for our chandelier.
哇,真是漂亮
Wow. It's gorgeous.
现在轮到布兰琪女士了
And now for Madame Blanche.
噢,我的天
Oh, my God.
布兰琪?
Blanche?
如果我说得太多 也许是因为你不说话
[Adamson] If I'm talking too much, perhaps it's because you're not talking.
我胃痛,亚瑟,它不同意谋杀
It's my stomach, Arthur. Murder doesn't agree with it.
你以为我很期待?
You think I'm looking forward to it?
如果乔森・马洛尼能干一点 他们现在早就都死了
If Joe Maloney had been more efficient, they'd both be dead by now.
你可以拿走我的那一份,亚瑟
You can have my share, Arthur.
你可以把两颗钻石都占为己有 只要你能结束一切
You can keep both diamonds all to yourself if you'll just end it.
我会告诉你该怎么做
I'll tell you what I'll do.
如果你帮我把这个睡美人 从地窖搬到我们的车上
If you help me carry Sleeping Beauty up out of the cellar, load her into our car...
开车送她去荒芜的公路 那些可以自杀的地方
and drive her out to some deserted road where a suicide can take place,
我向你保证 我们可以来讨论这件事
I promise you we'll talk this thing over.
- 好吗? - 计程车司机怎么办?
- Okay? - What about the cab driver?
如果她能找到我们 我相信他也可以
If she was able to find us, I'm sure he can too.
- 他逃不出我们的手掌心 - 是你的手,不是我的
- He'll walk right into our hands. - Your hands, not mine.
你不觉得我们 应该下去看一看她吗?
Don't you think we ought to go down and take a look at her?
自从我们给她注射以来 已经有一段时间了
It's been a while since we gave her that shot.
- 你去 - 好吧
- You do it. - Okay.
你会很高兴知道她仍然昏迷着
You'll be happy to know she's still unconscious.
- 布兰琪 - 嘘
[Whispers] - Blanche. - Shh!
我会这样结束,把管子的一端 接到排气管,另一端放在车窗中
I'll put this end into her exhaust pipe...
and the other end in the window.
这样看来就像是自杀
That way, it'll look like suicide.
最好现在就去把她带过来
Better go and get her now.
我要把她放在我们车里 你开她的
I'll take her in our car. You follow in hers.
你抓住她的双脚
You take hold of her feet.
老天,她还真重
Jesus, she's heavy. [Screaming]
乔治!
George!
抓到他们了
[Panting, Coughing] Got 'em.
布兰琪,你演的太好了
Blanche, you faked that one beautifully.
你仍然是冠军
You are still the champ.
谢谢,乔治
Thank you, George.
你知道这两个的赏金值多少吗?
Do you realize how much the reward is for those two?
是的
[Chuckling] Yes.
但是你知道,如果我们能够 找到钻石,还会有多少奖励吗?
But do you realize how much more the reward would be...
if we could find the diamonds and turn 'em in?
你怎么了?
What's the matter with you?
我…
I...
布兰琪,怎么回事?
Blanche, what's the matter?
怎么了?
What is it?
布兰琪,你办到了!
Blanche, you did it!
你真是个通灵师!
You are psychic!
- 我们在楼梯上干嘛? - 你不再是假的
- What am I doing here on the stairs? - You're not a fake.
你真的找到了一个,瞧
You actually found one. Look.
我找到的?
I did?
我要打电话给警察 告诉他们好消息
I'll get the police on the phone and give them our good news,
还要通知兰伯特女士 告诉她坏消息
and call Miss Rainbird and give her the bad.
接线生,能帮我接通警察局吗?
Operator, can I have the police?